<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog.atom"/>
  <title>Halfmoon Canada - The Balance Blog</title>
  <updated>2021-06-29T06:00:01-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Halfmoon Canada</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/an-ayurvedic-approach-to-yoga</id>
    <published>2021-06-29T06:00:01-07:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-12T09:35:17-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/an-ayurvedic-approach-to-yoga"/>
    <title>Balance Your Doshas With Ayurvedic Yoga</title>
    <author>
      <name>Stephanie Tung</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span style="font-weight: 400;">Learn how to ground and release stagnant energy with an Ayurvedic approach to yoga from instructor Kathryn Anne Flynn.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/an-ayurvedic-approach-to-yoga">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>A car is my favourite metaphor for describing the relationship between Ayurveda and yoga, the two Vedic sciences I study and love. Your bodymind is a vehicle, and this vehicle allows you to practice the yoga-asana, meditation, chanting, and ethical living that comprise yoga. </p>
<p>Yoga's history is replete with asana and pranayama techniques that may provide insight into the truth of the universe, but come with significant risk, too! Modern yoga-asana may emphasize accessibility, the value of gentleness, and restorative practices. Still, we know that many techniques and practice styles offer rewards that are not without risk of injury. </p>
<p>Whether you're practicing for liberation or stress-reduction (both great reasons), you need to care for your bodymind vehicle to keep it resilient. That's where Ayurveda comes in. </p>
<p>Āyurveda (आयुर्वेढ) is a compound Sanskrit word comprised of Ayus and Veda, which translates to <em>living wisdom</em>. The world's most ancient wellness/medical system, Āyurveda emphasizes prevention over treatment, but techniques range from dietary advice to surgeries. </p>
<p>The foundation of Āyurveda is that being made of nature, observing nature teaches us how to live in balance and harmony. Nature is built of five elements - space, air, fire, water, and earth - so we are also made from these elements. Elements express themselves in our psychological and physical makeup - some people are more earthy, for example, and have better memories than those with strong space element. Elements are more expressive in different seasons, people, and seasons of life - so balance is a commitment more than a destination.</p>
<p>Elements have particular qualities (<em>guṇa</em>) that describe how they behave. Fire is obviously hot, but in Āyurvedic parlance, it's also spreading, oily, sharp and penetrating. So when you drink too much coffee, skip breakfast, and then do a hot yoga session that leaves you with heartburn? That's fire element imbalance.  </p>
<p>An Āyurvedic approach to yoga can begin with observing how elements are related to our imbalances and how our yoga practice can promote harmony. Prop use is a beautiful way to promote psychological and physical balance through practice, so here are some ways you can take an Āyurvedic approach to yoga with props...</p>
<p><strong>Supported Legs Up with a Bolster</strong></p>
<p>When we feel frazzled, anxious, and overwhelmed, space and air elements may be dominant outside in nature or inside us. Space and air are both cold, light, dry and mobile, so this integrative posture promotes a sense of grounding. Use a large rectangular bolster, wear socks during cool weather or if you're a cold person, and use a blanket over your belly/hips. Notice how the bones of your legs root down into your pelvis as you practice a smooth breath. The heaviness and density of the props work at a psychological level, too, helping you feel grounded and nurtured. </p>
<p><strong>Block Vinyasa </strong> </p>
<p>When earth and water elements accumulate, they need sharp, strong practices to get moving since their qualities include sticky, heavy, and dense. When we're feeling stuck in a rut or have stagnant energy that needs moving, warming practices like Vinyasa yoga are helpful. Trying new things also helps us get into a new groove. By placing blocks under our hands, we change up the challenge and try something new! Playfulness has a light quality to it, which is balancing for earth and water elements. </p>
<p><strong>Babbling Brook</strong></p>
<p>Backbending can help clear accumulated earth and water elements in our lungs and chest, which may make us feel congested. However, many backbends can also create too much space, making us feel untethered rather than balanced. If you need a backbend to clear space through your chest in a more balanced way, babbling brook restorative posture can do just that. With a folded blanket under your head for neck support, use a horizontal bolster or rolled-up blanket under your ribs for the backbend that promotes lightness. Also use a bolster under your knees to promote low back support, which promotes stability. You want to feel held by your props - if your neck is tensing to "hold" you in place, you need more support under your head, a lower backbend prop, or to bring your hips up using a blanket under your bum. </p>
<p><strong>Eye Pillows in Savasana </strong></p>
<p>Each element has different areas in the body where it tends to accumulate more than others. When this happens, we feel it in our bodymind. For example, fire element accumulates in the eyes. We know this from too much screen time (dry eyes, sharp feelings in our eye muscles, headaches, etc.). We also see this during fiery yoga practices, where students' eye ferocity increases during postures like Warrior II! </p>
<p>You can cool fire element in the eyes by making your gaze (<em>drishti)</em> more gentle during standing sequences, but an eye pillow over your eyes in Savasana can be practiced at any time. Whether it's the end of your practice or the end of the day, this helps cool and contain fire element. </p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>—Kathryn Anne Flynn</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>For further reading, pick up Mona Warner's <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/%C4%80yurvedic-Yoga-Approaches-Teaching/dp/1999427203"><em>Āyurvedic Yoga: 3 Approaches to Teaching Āyurvedic Yoga</em></a> and Kathryn Anne Flynn's <em><a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Teach-Kind-Clear-Kathryn-Flynn/dp/1777403103">Teach Kind, Clear Yoga: A Guide for Practitioners and Teachers</a>. </em> </p>
<p>Kathryn Anne Flynn is a teacher of yoga, Ayurveda, meditation, future psychotherapist, and student of all. Known for her articulate and compassionate voice, she draws on her years of experience and practice tools to help educate others on their yoga journey.⁠</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/anti-racism-in-action-with-kim-katrin</id>
    <published>2020-11-23T11:48:09-08:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-07T14:20:46-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/anti-racism-in-action-with-kim-katrin"/>
    <title>Anti-Racism in Action with Kim Katrin</title>
    <author>
      <name>Taelor Gray</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><b><i>Kim sat down with our Partnerships &amp; Community lead, Connor to discuss and share more about how she got started as an anti-racist educator, how her yoga practice informs her work and three key pieces of advice she offers health &amp; wellness professionals who are looking to make their spaces and programs more accessible. You can watch the full 3-Part Series on our Instagram TV - @shophalfmoon.</i></b><meta charset="utf-8"><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/anti-racism-in-action-with-kim-katrin">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><b><i>Kim Katrin is a multidisciplinary activist, artist, educator and yogi. She is an inspiring advocate for anti-racist, queer, trans and feminist issues. She has spoken at various panels, conferences and universities across North America, contributing to publications such as Cosmo, MTV and Buzzfeed and she has been working with us here at Halfmoon over the past several weeks supporting our commitment to Anti-Racism, Diversity and Inclusion. </i></b></p>
<p><b><i>Kim sat down with our Partnerships &amp; Community lead Connor to discuss and share more about how she got started as an anti-racist educator, how her yoga practice informs her work and three key pieces of advice she offers health &amp; wellness professionals who are looking to make their spaces and programs more accessible. You can watch the full 3-Part Series on our Instagram TV - @shophalfmoon. </i></b></p>
<p><b><i>Here are some highlights from the conversation below! </i></b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I think at the core, the work that I do is really a commitment to equity and to human rights and wanting to work with people in ways that feel really meaningful and also are really transformative. I like working with people really to help support them on their own healing journeys. When I'm working in spaces that are around anti-racism or equity or justice, I'm really interested in helping people engage in uncomfortable dialogue in ways that can be really healing.I have a skincare line too so even that is about self-care and healing. And there is a really clear theme in a lot of the things that I do, because it comes from a place of genuinely really caring about people and wanting to see us have healthier relationships and have more of a commitment to love and to justice in the ways that we work with.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think Tony Morrison says, “activism is kind of our rent for being on the planet”. And I sort of think about it like that. I feel really called and I think we should all feel really called to move out of humility and to be in service to other people, because it really does give life this incredible meaning. That's really where you feel like, wow, this is part of my purpose in being here on this planet for such a short amount of time. I am always asking myself the question of what am I leaving behind? Like, what is the legacy of what we're doing here with each other? And I think that when we are in service to each other and in service to a broader vision, then you can really have a sense of what your purpose is, why you're here and how we can really support healthy connections with each other. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When I was younger, I started to really ask questions of, how did it come to be that all of these different cultures are within me. My mom is Venezuelan and East Indian and my dad is Scottish and Dominican. So when I started to ask those questions, that was really when I started to understand ideas around colonization or the Transatlantic Slave Trade, or just understanding the movement of people. And then when I went to university, I became very interested in understanding genocide and a lot of human rights issues.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I visited Auschwitz in Poland and I really wanted to understand what made people do horrible things to each other. Like if we are all connected, we're all human beings, we're all the shared species. But over time we've seen obviously great acts of love, but we've also seen like incredible acts of hate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And I really wanted to understand why that was happening and what was the root of those kinds of movements and the more I think about it the more I felt like I always knew where I was going. And the more that I knew, the more that I learned, the more that I wanted to share. I love learning. And I was so excited and so passionate about it. And I recognize that learning wasn't always that kind of experience for most people. So I really wanted to make learning accessible and make this information accessible and hopefully work in a way that helps people come together. Right now, this is such an intense time in our history and you see a lot of violence happening, but also you see these really beautiful, beautiful movements of people trying to do better. And I've always been on the side of that. I understand that there are going to be violent things that happen in the world, but there's so many of us who really want to do better. And how can I be a part of that? How can I amplify and accelerate this movement of people in the world who really do want to do better and care about each other and believe that we need each other.”</span></p>
<p><b>Connor: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">When our capacity to experience violence expands, it also means that there is an opportunity to expand our capacity to love. It’s not just one or the other. So with all the things that are happening there is so much beauty in being able to explore new ways of educating and opening up new ways of having these conversations. I often find that there is a moment or a time specifically that draws an individual to the practice of yoga. So how did you come to discover your yoga practice and how has that informed, not only your life experience, but really your work and your service?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I think that yoga had always been around me in different ways, but I didn't become  connected to it until I was at university and a friend of mine let me know that she was going to a yoga class. Her name was Coco Finaldi and she was a new mom and she taught the class with her baby, like strapped to her chest. And I just remember being totally in awe because her baby was just blissed out. It was just so peaceful. Baby was just breathing with us. Smiling with us. And it was one of these really transformative moments for me, because I'd always been very athletic. I was a cheerleader in high school. I did dance and gymnastics. And so I always loved movement in my body. When I got into yoga for the first time, the combination of movement and meditation was just, well you know, you have to be present with your breath. You have to be present in the moment and every time you wander off you have to just come back. There's something about the practice that keeps you coming back to being in your body. And I think one of the things that has always been important is, yoga is a tool for working through and around trauma. Because if you are somebody who's experienced trauma, you don't necessarily feel super safe in your body. And yoga was and is this practice where I feel safe in my body. I felt like I wanted to be there. And it wasn't about what my body looked like. Dance and gymnastics is very much what you look like, the performance of it, which is super fun and I love that because I love that performance, but it wasn't about what I looked like. “</span></p>
<p><b><i>3 Things Health Professionals Can Do To Make Space More Accessible </i></b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before we begin conversations with others. We want to have these conversations with ourselves. And so one of the things I always talk to people about is having a journaling practice. Do that kind of shadow work, ask yourself questions. One of the things I always invite people to ask themselves is, identify a person that you don't like and write down why you don't like them and then go back through it and identify what traits you think you also have. Because I think that one of the challenges is that when we’re trying to talk to and change other people, you have to check your energy. Before you begin the conversation, ask yourself, are you trying to make yourself feel good and give yourself more power in this relationship?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I used to talk about this a lot. Hurt people, hurt people, but healed people, heal people, you know? So if you're really starting to begin to have these conversations with people in your life, you really gotta be very invested in your own healing and your own honesty with yourself.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I had to be honest, like why did racism mean so much to me? Like, Oh, okay. It has a lot to do with me feeling like I needed to learn more about who I was and I felt untethered in a particular kind of way. And so I had to be really honest about those things before I could go out and talk to people, because I also had to tell people where my prejudice was. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Are you one of those people who gets really annoyed every time you have to wait for someone else? Like you have to find those things in yourself because that's where you'll connect to other people. Have a different thought, change your mind, change your approach. And when you can share with people that you're struggling with it too, that you work on it too, then people can feel not that this person is better than me but rather they’re trying like me. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are three things health and wellness professionals can do to make spaces more accessible. </span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Understanding the importance of access.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Access is so crucial. Accessibility is so crucial. Even physical accessibility. I think that sometimes we, especially when we're in fitness and wellness, we like to put it out of our minds that at one point in our life, we probably will experience some kind of disability.We feel like we’re super strong and we have muscle, our yoga game is just on point and we can’t imagine a time where things might not look like that for us. Recognizing that so many people are dealing with that all the time, a lot of the time we shut that out because it’s our own internal fear. So just really thinking about the design, when you make things more accessible you increase the experience for everyone. You’re also creating a world you want to live in, in the future too. So it’s important that it’s not just for you, it’s for everyone in your community. </span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">2. Admit when you don’t know what you’re doing. </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I would say it’s good to admit when you don’t know what you’re doing, to be able to say as a studio owner, or if you own a gym that you don’t know what you’re doing. It’s ok to say I’m learning more about anti-racism, or how not to be sexist, but I don’t actually know what I’m doing. I’m doing my best and I’m trying to figure it out. I'm really open to having feedback and I'm really happy to talk to people about it. But I don't know what I'm doing. I think that that's one of those things I'm really nervous about or I'm really scared of. And I'm really worried about what other people are gonna think about me.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tell people the truth. I think a lot of the times we feel like we have to have it all together. So when people announce like an issue, they're like, Oh, this is what we're going to do. And it's going to be great. And then if someone critiques it, they're like. I tried so hard. How could you, how could you be upset at how hard I tried?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whereas if you were able to say, we're trying out this initiative, I've never done anything like this before I'm personally really afraid and it might not work out or people might be upset about it, but I'm trying to be vulnerable. And I look forward to hearing back from you and hopefully we can create a space where we can honestly talk about it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just lay it out on the table versus trying to act like you have it all together. This is the most beautiful solution. </span></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">3. Recognize that practice makes improvement.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re going to continue to work on it, continue to get better, but know that we’re never going to be perfect. These issues around inequities in our world literally took hundreds of years for us to get to this place. We’re actually doing a really good job, I think, at engaging in this and trying to unpack it and figure it out. There's obviously there's people who don't want to unpack these things and we can’t do anything about it, you can’t make people do things that they don’t want to do, but we can set really clear boundaries about what we’ll allow in our spaces and what we won’t allow in our spaces. I think that having integrity is making the choice that is more difficult and more uncomfortable but will be better for us in the long run. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes I think we just want the fun part. We want to get into the super fun part, but it’s when you do the work and you lay the foundation that the fun afterwards is so much more liberating and so much more rewarding. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do the hard work with each other first. Hard work is what builds real relationships. When you go through something difficult with someone you are bonded. You struggled with someone and they now have your back. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So I think that sometimes we feel like the only way we'll have great relationships is if we only do fun stuff together, but it's actually not true. It’s doing the difficult things that builds the stuff that makes you feel like you can trust someone to really do the fun things. </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/sounds-good-how-to-use-singing-bowls-for-your-meditation-with-phair-yoga</id>
    <published>2020-09-14T17:04:59-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-09-14T17:17:43-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/sounds-good-how-to-use-singing-bowls-for-your-meditation-with-phair-yoga"/>
    <title>Sound&apos;s Good: How to Use Singing Bowls for Your Meditation with Phair Yoga</title>
    <author>
      <name>Taelor Gray</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Using a singing bowl adds another layer of ritual to your meditation, which can help to prime your mind and body for practice. This can be especially helpful if you’ve been finding it challenging to make the transition from “regular life” into your self-practice.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/sounds-good-how-to-use-singing-bowls-for-your-meditation-with-phair-yoga">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="p1">Using a singing bowl adds another layer of ritual to your meditation, which can help to prime your mind and body for practice. This can be especially helpful if you’ve been finding it challenging to make the transition from “regular life” into your self-practice.</p>
<p class="p3"><b>How do we use it in our meditations?</b></p>
<p class="p1">A home meditation practice relies on consistency and for many, a ritual to help set the tone for some quiet time. Make your space comfortable and inviting. It’s ok if you don’t have a specific area that is “only” for your meditation practice. Before you practice, set up your space with items that make you feel good and help you to ground. When you are ready to begin, start by lightly striking the bowl. This simple action can help signal the start of your meditation, and over time, that sound can help condition the mind and body to relax quicker.  You can continue to play the singing bowl throughout the meditation, waiting for each strike to completely fade, if you feel like you need help focusing. </p>
<p class="p1">If you want to better feel the vibration of the sound, make the bowl sing by lightly striking the bowl and slowly run the soft part of the mallet around the edge until you hear the bowl singing softly. Less is more here. The sound can be piercing if you move too quickly. When the meditation draws to a close, lightly strike the bowl a final time and allow for a moment of silent contemplation.  </p>
<p class="p3"><b>Benefits of Sound Healing</b></p>
<p class="p1">All behaviours, both on and off the mat/cushion, are attempts to come into resonance with the universal energy field (UEF). When our bodies lose resonance with this UEF, there is a loss of energy and vitality. One of the principals of sound healing is that all physical, mental, and emotional symptoms are being generated by underlying energy fields. If we change this energy field we are able to change the associated physical, mental, and emotional patterns as well. In layman terms, think about what you feel in your body and mind when you listen to a sad song vs. a happy song. Singing bowls are tuned to create a resonance that is pleasant and that has a calming effect, helping you set the stage for meditation.</p>
<p class="p1">In the end, how you use the bowl and set up your meditation space, is up to you. Establish your own rituals or follow traditions you feel connected to.</p>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<meta charset="utf-8">
<span size="4" style="font-size: large;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/image_99d2da4d-5e3f-43d5-8392-bfdacf1492a2_480x480.jpg?v=1600128091" width="480x480" height="480x480" style="margin-right: 10px; float: left;"></span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/jonathanphair/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.instagram.com/jonathanphair/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1600214180550000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGAk377sAxA-F1KnK2Kuq3JGZibDA" rel="noopener noreferrer">@jonathanphair</a><span> and </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/queeniephair/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.instagram.com/queeniephair/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1600214180550000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHwTx-J2oasABRPJ-FCVe595kQbbQ" rel="noopener noreferrer">@queeniephair</a><span> are Toronto-based yoga teachers. They both believe that yoga is much more than being able to do advanced postures. The adventure-loving duo are first and foremost students of yoga. After developing a regular practice they realized how awesome it is to share their passion, to inspire others to move, and to live a healthier, happier life. Find them in studios all over Toronto, and leading retreats all over the world with </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/focusretreats/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.instagram.com/focusretreats/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1600214180550000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEhFR45XvDk70K4HfvjTTokdHDK9Q" rel="noopener noreferrer">@focusretreats</a><span>! Join them for online classes and more </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/phairyoga/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.instagram.com/phairyoga/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1600214180550000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF0jderyi7U3Ni37qS-6k0TWc1tbg" rel="noopener noreferrer">@phairyoga</a><span> or check out their YouTube channel over at </span><a href="http://www.youtube.com/c/phairyoga" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.youtube.com/c/phairyoga&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1600214180550000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF4SqHrOvsIpMqPnx7IStFEFeidpw" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.youtube.com/c/phairyoga</a><span>.</span>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/finding-your-inner-voice-with-samantha-stevenson</id>
    <published>2020-08-21T10:27:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-08-21T10:27:30-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/finding-your-inner-voice-with-samantha-stevenson"/>
    <title>Finding Your Inner Voice with Samantha Stevenson</title>
    <author>
      <name>Taelor Gray</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Finding my inner voice is a journey I’m continuing to navigate. Like many of you, it’s been a process of self-reflection and self-learning. It has been interesting, fun, challenging, and sometimes absolutely exhausting. It is an act of returning to myself — a process of going inward.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/finding-your-inner-voice-with-samantha-stevenson">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[Finding my inner voice is a journey I’m continuing to navigate. Like many of you, it’s been a process of self-reflection and self-learning. It has been interesting, fun, challenging, and sometimes absolutely exhausting. It is an act of returning to myself. For me, it’s been a process of going inward and seeing what's really going on, what parts of me I am ready to explore. <br><br>The self-reflection has been the most important element of finding my inner voice. I’ve become curious and started to ask myself inquiring questions about my life and parts of my experiences. I’ve found that the inner voice can be as subtle as a whisper or as loud as a scream. It’s about listening and coming to know what my inner voice sounds like versus what my ‘monkey mind’ is telling me. The inner voice of my highest self is always leading and guiding me to where I need to be. <br><br>I have and still am developing a sense of self-trust. A knowing that when something comes up, whatever it is, that I am safe and that everything will be okay. In this way, I have come to know my heart, know my intentions and I’ve spent enough time with my inner voice that it feels comfortable coming into material form through my speech and writing, in conversation, and in my actions. I give myself permission to take center stage, to live in joy and gratitude, patience and abundance. I feel aligned and comfortable sharing my voice when I feel safe and secure within myself, knowing that my voice is valued, necessary and can engage meaningfully with the external world. <br><br>Here are 5 ways I’ve been doing this work to find my inner voice: <br><br><strong>1. Learning from other’s and understanding intersectional perspectives helps guide me with my own internal work</strong><br> <br>I don’t try to reinvent the wheel and do this work alone, there are some amazing guides out there that are doing the work to support people in finding their way back to themselves. By these people sharing their experiences and what’s worked for them, it’s been incredibly helpful and healing in my own experience. Most recently, I’ve been following the guidance of Maryam Hasnaa’s New Earth Mystery School and Monique Ruffin aka the Moon Mama. Both of their offerings have been incredibly helpful, offering tools that have supported my own personal journey. <br> <br><strong>2. Yoga &amp; Meditation: clearing the chaos, releasing what’s not meant for me and seeking sovereignty</strong> <br> <br>I invite my inner voice to come forward when I am able to decrease the noise and find quiet and stillness. I use yoga and meditation as a means to this. Through both of these modalities, I’m able to quiet my mind’s chatter. In my personal practice, I have been inspired by energy clearing through visualization meditations. These have been extremely helpful in learning how to manage my energetic sovereignty better. In this society, it is very easy to absorb a lot of energies and opinions of others so for me, it has become very important to come to know what’s mine and what’s not. This is an important tool I’ve used in finding my inner voice, clearing my channel so my real essence can come forward. <br><br><strong>3. Fine-tuning my intuition through tarot and oracle reading, paying attention to everyday synchronicities</strong> <br> <br>My intuition and my inner voice are deeply connected. Fine-tuning my intuition has definitely been a helpful component in finding my voice. Lately, I’ve practiced listening and reflection through mediums such as oracle cards or tarot decks, paying attention to the synchronicities, the numerology, symbols, astrology. The subtleties in everyday life deepen my relationship to the self, my intuition, and my inner voice. <br><br><strong>4. Following my gut, leading with the heart</strong> <br> <br>For me, dancing, laughter, watching inspiring content, having soulful conversations with friends and family, playing with my dog, cozy alone time and self-care are some of the things that feel good to me. I like to ask myself “what’s the most exciting thing I could do right now” and this brings me into alignment with the frequency I desire most and from this place, my inner voice, my true self can come through. <br><br><strong>5. Letting myself feel free, being playful and feeling safe</strong> <br> <br>I feel empowered to shine when I give myself the permission to be free - to tap into my playful and light-heartedness. In these moments of presence I allow myself to feel fully myself, to speak from a place of joy and contentment. Allow yourself and give yourself the permission to feel free; get outside, do the things you love, spend time with the people who inspire you. <br><br>Life is a journey and I’m learning to have fun with it and enjoy the ride. I’m wishing anyone who reads this ease and fun in tuning into your inner voice, it's in there ready to come out and play. Trust yourself and be well. <br><br><br><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/Screenshot_2020-08-18_at_1.55.12_PM_medium.png?v=1597784124" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px;">Bio: Samantha Stevenson (she/her) is trauma-informed yoga and meditation student and teacher based currently in Maryland. She is a wellness advocate and budding creative. She is also a brand strategist and digital content creator and manager. Mostly, she is a divine being having a human experience finding her way like the rest of us, who is in gratitude to her community. <br><br><a href="https://www.instagram.com/vraibleu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Find Samantha on Instagram here.</a>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/self-massage-at-home</id>
    <published>2020-04-23T15:41:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-23T15:42:05-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/self-massage-at-home"/>
    <title>Self Massage at Home with Alexa Yuel</title>
    <author>
      <name>Taelor Gray</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Massage Therapy is an easy and feel good modality that helps treat soft tissue trauma in our body. This can be as microscopic as an adhesion in our skeletal muscle tissue that is causing pain, referral pain or a headache, and as obvious as a muscle stuck in contracture that causes what we refer to as a knot that seems to roll under your touch. We put our bodies through a lot, and physical stress like working out or even the physical stress from our jobs (whether it’s sitting all day or moving), as well as mental and emotional stress, can store itself in our bodies as tension.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/self-massage-at-home">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #444444;">Massage Therapy is an easy and feel good modality that helps treat soft tissue trauma in our body. This can be as microscopic as an adhesion in our skeletal muscle tissue that is causing pain, referral pain or a headache, and as obvious as a muscle stuck in contracture that causes what we refer to as a knot that seems to roll under your touch. We put our bodies through a lot, and physical stress like working out or even the physical stress from our jobs (whether it’s sitting all day or moving), as well as mental and emotional stress, can store itself in our bodies as tension.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">We are so lucky that the physical therapy industry is booming, access to massage, physio, athletic and occupational therapists, chiropractors, reflexologists, osteopaths and yoga studios (just to name a few), is so easy. While it is important to use these physical modalities to our advantage, and as much as we can, the time you spend with these professionals is only a small fraction of your day, week, month, even your year. This is why it is important to have a few of your favourite tools at home, to use daily to keep your soft tissues pliable and free of pain.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"><b>Benefits of Massage</b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">The benefits of massage therapy are endless. Our body is so complex with so many systems and nerve impulses working together every single second, and massage therapy seeks to make sure everything is working in harmony and equally. Physical massage helps to increase circulation of our blood and oxygen to muscle tissue (think of warming up before a workout), it increases circulation of our lymphatic fluid which is important for our immune system because lymphatic fluid moves and filters out bacteria and toxins from our blood stream. Circulation also helps stimulate our bodies natural healing/inflammatory process. Massage therapy helps decrease our sensation and perception of pain. Treatment might feel painful in the moment, but all those little nerve sensors are helping to dull the pain. As mentioned before massage therapy is important in increasing the pliability of our muscle tissue and decreasing tension of the fascial system in our bodies. Mentally massage increases production of “feel good hormones” like serotonin and dopamine and decreases the cortisol (stress) hormone. All these amazing benefits are within our reach at home, and this is why it is important to try to do a little bit of self massage at home as much as you can! I have been using various therapy tools at home for years, and I am lucky enough that Halfmoon asked me to try out some of their latest therapy tools, and tell you about what they are best used for from a Massage Therapists perspective!</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"><b>How to Get the Same Benefits of Massage at Home</b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">It is relatively easy if you have the right tools! I tell my clients to play around with the tools they have, you really can’t go wrong or do any damage. All you need to do is monitor your pressure and intensity, if it feels painful, then just ease off to your appropriate level of discomfort and relief, and avoid massaging over bony prominences like your patella, hip bone, and spinous processes.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"><b>Foam Roller</b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">Used best for: Large surface areas such as the IT band, glutes, mid - lower erectors, quadriceps and hamstring groups. I love the length of this foam roller as small-medium sized foam rollers are easier to maneuver and control, and the thickness provides a larger surface area and support. The material of the Halfmoon foam roller is firm yet flexible which provides some give. It is fairly easy to monitor your intensity on the foam roller, if you are up on your hands the pressure will be less intense than if you are down on your elbows.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;">  </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"><b>Cork Roller</b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">Used best for: Smaller surface areas such as the calves, anterior compartment of lower legs (shin area) and bottom of feet. This roller can also be used on the large muscles of the body for increased intensity (compared to the foam roller), and for occipital/suboccipital (back of the head), release for headaches and lymphatic sinus drainage.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">This roller was easy to play around with, I found this to be one of the most versatile tools out of what I tried. The material is firm, so not a lot of give which increases the intensity of the pressure, and since it is not very thick it can really dig into the deeper muscle layers. I really got creative with this roller and found I could use it as an awesome calf stretch (one foot on ground and stretching foot on roller with same heel on the ground and lean in), and as a psoas (hip flexor) release by turning the roller vertical, kneeling into a lunge position and leaning my abdomen into the edge of the roller. This last use was my favourite use for the roller as I find self psoas release to be the most challenging to accomplish.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"><b>Large Rubber Ball</b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">Used best for: Rolling the Glute area to reach deeper muscles such as the Piriformis, and trigger point therapy.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">It is easy to use this ball on virtually all muscles of the body. For a medium intensity it is best to use the ball standing between you and the wall, and for a higher intensity laying down between you and the floor.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">Bonus: if you had 2 of these balls, you can place one under each glute, and to monitor the intensity and to lay with pressure for an extended amount of time (using breath work), place a bolster, foam/cork block or folded up blanket under upper back and head.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"><b>Peanut Roller</b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">Used best for: Posterior head and neck, and SI joint area (bilateral).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">This tool is my personal favourite, there are so many different ways to use this roller. For the posterior head and neck I found it best for bilateral occipital and suboccipital release (more lymphatic and sinus drainage, and release for headaches), as well as bilateral work to the SI joints and multifidus of the sacrum. I even used it on the Frontal area of the head (think forehead), to release sinuses more and relieve headache pain.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">Bonus: To monitor the intensity and to lay with pressure for an extended amount of time (using breath work): Peanut roller used under upper body: bolster, foam/cork block or folded up blanket to support sacrum/hips, and support upper body and head if peanut roller used at sacrum.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"><b>Cork Massage Trio (2 medium and 1 small)</b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">Used best for: Trigger point release of virtually any muscle.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">The small surface area of the balls means it is easy to pinpoint certain areas of pain and trauma. This is used best if you have a specific area where you can feel a “knot”. For a more easily controlled application of pressure and intensity it is best to use one ball standing, used between you and the wall. For a more intense pressure, use laying down. Between you and the floor. You can use any size for any area of the body, but I find that the medium sized ball is best for any area of the mid - lower back, glutes, and legs, and the small ball is best for the upper back and neck. These cork balls are also great to use to roll under your hand for the pec muscles and upper arms.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">Bonus: Use the medium sized balls under each glute, and to monitor the intensity and to lay with pressure for an extended amount of time (using breath work), place a bolster, foam/cork block or folded up blanket under upper back and head (can do the same with the 2 balls at same level of the back, and support under the sacrum).</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"><b>Happy Rolling!</b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #444444;">These amazing tools from Halfmoon can help you take your tissue health to the next level. Get creative! Like mentioned before, you really can’t go wrong or do any damage. Your body won’t regret the help, but as always, monitor the intensity you feel, everyone has a different threshold for that mild massage discomfort. You can stay within your comfort zone, or push that discomfort a little bit. Our body needs movement, and this is another way to move your tissues and support the important symptoms that keep us functioning!</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #444444;"> </span></p>
<p style="float: left;"><span style="color: #444444;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/alexa_medium.jpg?v=1587595686" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px;">Alexa Yuel (Dutchak) is a Registered Massage Therapist and Kinesiologist in Winnipeg. She has been an RMT for 3 years, and was also a Certified Personal Trainer and group exercise instructor for several years previous to graduating Massage Therapy College. She has her own private practice where she treats clients and also helps them develop at home strategies for muscle and tissue health through exercise, stretching and self massage. She combines a spa atmosphere and special touch with clinical assessment and practices for her clients.  You can find Alexa on Instagram @dynamicwellnesswpg_rmt and through her <a href="https://dynamicwellnesswpg.janeapp.com" target="_blank" style="color: #444444;" rel="noopener noreferrer">online booking site, by clicking here.</a></span></p>
<br><br><br>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/7-ways-to-connect-with-nature-this-earth-day</id>
    <published>2020-04-21T14:22:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-22T16:04:26-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/7-ways-to-connect-with-nature-this-earth-day"/>
    <title>7 Ways to Connect with Nature this Earth Day with Eoin Finn</title>
    <author>
      <name>Taelor Gray</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>As our beaches and parks get shut down, the preciousness of nature seems even more important. If anything will keep us sane and healthy right now it is the forests, the trees and the wide-open seas. My hope is that we always take the time to observe the beauty of nature. Even if we are locked inside, we can still look up at the clouds and the stars; and see the immense beauty that we are a part of. We can feel the gift of the green leafy trees in every breath we take</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/7-ways-to-connect-with-nature-this-earth-day">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As our beaches and parks get shut down, the preciousness of nature seems even more important. If anything will keep us sane and healthy right now it is the forests, the trees and the wide-open seas. My hope is that we always take the time to observe the beauty of nature. Even if we are locked inside, we can still look up at the clouds and the stars; and see the immense beauty that we are a part of. We can feel the gift of the green leafy trees in every breath we take.  </span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span>If the last few months have taught us anything it is the degree to which nothing in the world happens in isolation. As a species we need to be reminded that we are just guests on this planet, and we are not masters. As Chief Seattle famously reminded us, “we did not weave the web of life, we are merely a strand.”</span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ultimately, Yoga and Ecology are both saying the same things; we are all interconnected. We need to get unstuck from our own selfish ego needs and see the joy of harmony with all life.  </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><b>What are some things we can do this Earth Day? Here’s my list.</b></p>
<p><strong>Relish Nature Appreciation Moments:</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Quiet times in Nature, what I call Nature Appreciation Moments, are the foundation of my yoga practice. Slowing down and observing Nature opens the door to presence. It steers our consciousness from feeling trapped inside a head full of problems to an expansive experience of awe, joy and wonder.  An intimate relationship with nature is the foundation of physical and emotional well-being. This is especially true now when we have so much anxiety in our lives.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jacques Cousteau famously said, “we protect what we revere.” He’s right.  Nature Appreciation moments allow us to download the doctrine of beauty into our hearts.  But it’s a two-way street. When we are more connected to nature, we will be better stewards for the planet we love.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I always tell people that this essential step is where all environmentalism starts; getting quiet in nature and letting our deepest heart become clear.</span></p>
<br>
<p><strong>Keep Zooming: </strong></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first thing that comes to my mind to minimize our carbon footprint, is by using habits that we have already established in “lockdown.”  It’s become clear that meetings can happen by Skype, Facetime and Zoom. Do we really need to take that business trip across town, across the country or across the globe to have a meeting? Is there a video conference that would suffice? I am committing to offering way more online training and courses long after the pandemic peaks.  </span></p>
<br>
<p><strong>Reduce Only:</strong></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A commitment I am making is to not rely so much on recycling and even reuse but instead go straight to the reduced part of the 3R’s of sustainability.  Recycling is better than </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">not</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> recycling, no doubt. But a challenge we have made in our family is just to reduce. To try to skip recycle all together. Instead of buying three bottles of kombucha for five dollars each, we make our own kombucha at home and save the energy it takes to recycle glass. We make our own sauerkraut and even yogurt. We buy bread from the local bakery bringing our own bags and even beer gets refilled at our local craft brewery in growlers we own. The great thing is, we end up saving a ton of money this way too! </span></p>
<br>
<p><strong>Carry Utensils and Cups:</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Get a fanny pack! No, the fanny pack itself won’t save the planet but what you can carry in it will help. I always have a set of bamboo utensils and a drinking straw in my fanny pack. In my backpack, I carry a reusable coffee cup and a water bottle.  </span></p>
<br>
<p><strong>Vote with Your Dollars:</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Support companies that make an effort to use less packaging, no toxic chemicals and who give back to the planet. The more we show that we care by how we spend our money, the more we can help shape a world where businesses have a more positive relationship to our precious environment.  </span></p>
<br>
<p><strong>Eat Locally and Aim at Growing Some of your Food:</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s better for you and your microbiome. There is so much goodness that comes by being connected to your ecosystem. Foraging and growing food (even a few planters of herbs in your kitchen window will do) with friends and family brings back a simple joy that is deep in our biology.  </span></p>
<br>
<p><strong>Get Involved:</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Donating money to organizations is fine but meeting people and rolling up your sleeves is incredibly rewarding. Find a group you connect with and join them. E.g. At a beach cleanup in your neighbourhood. A few years ago I started the EcoKarma foundation where we do yoga in the morning and environmental impact work like coral transplanting, mangrove restoration and beach cleanups.  The joy from working together with a group of like-minded people to take care of the planet is unparalleled. It is my antidepressant and gives me hope for the future we can create for ourselves and this planet we call home.   </span></p>
<p> </p>
<meta charset="utf-8"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/Eoin_medium.jpg?v=1587421906" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px;">
<p>Eoin Finn is a globally renowned yogi, surfer and Blissologist who has been carving his original tracks through the metaphysical worlds of yoga, philosophy and movement since 1989. Lauded by Yoga Journal as the “Thoreau of Yoga” for his eco-activism and dedication to connecting yogis more deeply to the spirituality of nature; and by Oprah as “one to watch,” Finn’s Blissology Yoga style centers on the simple idea of sharing happiness. <a href="https://blissology.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">You can find Eoin and what he is up to next, on his website, here.</a></p>
<p>Photos of Eoin by Meredith Rose.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/yoga-props-that-every-beginner-needs</id>
    <published>2020-04-13T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-13T14:04:23-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/yoga-props-that-every-beginner-needs"/>
    <title>Yoga Props That Every Beginner Needs with Kate Gillespie</title>
    <author>
      <name>Amanda Vitaro</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>There are countless ways that props can support your at home yoga practice. From your very first day on your mat to decades of dedicated practice, </span><span>each yoga prop can serve a multitude of purposes. However, there are always the essentials. </span><span>Here are a few suggestions to get you started. </span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/yoga-props-that-every-beginner-needs">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><b></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are countless ways that props can support your at home yoga practice. From your very first day on your mat to decades of dedicated practice, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">each yoga prop can serve a multitude of purposes. However, there are always the essentials. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are a few suggestions to get you started. </span></p>
<p><b>A Yoga Mat</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First and foremost, you’ll need a yoga mat. Your own little sanctuary that will travel with you everywhere. My top pick for a yoga mat is the </span><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/b-yoga-mats"><span style="font-weight: 400;">B MAT Everyday</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. I’ve tried dozens of different mats over the years, and this one stands out as my favourite. This mat offers the best grip of any mat I’ve ever owned, the perfect amount of cushioning, and it’s relatively light compared to other mats of the same thickness. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Plus, it comes in a variety of beautiful colours! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The B MAT also comes in </span><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/b-yoga-mats/products/b-mat-traveller-2mm-7?variant=31774791008316"><span style="font-weight: 400;">travel form</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and is the one I recommend to all of my yoga retreat guests. It’s light, easy to pack and has the same superior grip as the Everyday version.</span></p>
<p><b>Blocks</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A set of 2 blocks will open up so many possibilities for your yoga practice. One of the primary functions of a </span><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/products/cork-yoga-block-natural-cork?_pos=1&amp;_sid=c7ad623c1&amp;_ss=r"><span style="font-weight: 400;">yoga block</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is to bring the floor closer to you. For example, in a low lunge or a forward fold when you are asked to have your hands on the floor, but your hands just won’t get there, the block brings the ground up by 3 or 4 inches. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blocks give you support and stability in a variety of postures. In a cross legged seat, ideally the knees are lower than the hips so that the hip flexors can relax, so sitting up on a block can be a big help.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a reclined butterfly pose (Supta Baddha Konasana), the support of 2 blocks underneath the outer thighs will help to facilitate softening in the inner thighs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of my other favourite ways to use blocks is in a supported heart opener. One block underneath the back of the heart and the other block under the back of your head. This sets up a beautiful opening across the front of the chest.</span></p>
<p><b>Strap</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A </span><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/products/8-loop-yoga-strap-organic-cotton-1?_pos=5&amp;_sid=9d937fe39&amp;_ss=r"><span style="font-weight: 400;">yoga strap</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is another versatile prop that will be immensely useful in your practice.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The most basic function of a yoga strap is to extend the length of your arms. For example, when you are lying on your back and asked to grab your foot in a hamstring stretch (Supta Padangustasana), most of us simply can’t reach without sacrificing good form. Instead, loop a strap around the sole of your foot and hold it in your hand. This logic also works in standing poses where you are asked to grab your foot, such as balancing on one leg and holding your foot out in front of you, or holding your foot in dancer’s pose when the leg is behind you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For tighter shoulders, interlacing your hands behind your back can seem like an impossible task. Holding a strap in both hands can make this posture accessible.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having a longer strap of at least 8 feet opens up more possibilities to use the strap in more creative ways. By using the buckle on your strap to create a big loop, you can re-create the same hamstring stretch (Supta Padangustasana) without having to use your hands. Place the looped strap underneath your shoulder blades and take one foot up in the strap at a time.</span></p>
<p><b>Bolster</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A </span><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/products/8-loop-yoga-strap-organic-cotton-1?_pos=5&amp;_sid=9d937fe39&amp;_ss=r"><span style="font-weight: 400;">bolster</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a must-have for your restorative practice. The goal of restorative yoga is to relax into postures without any strain, which is facilitated by the aid of props. When you relax into restorative poses, your parasympathetic nervous system is stimulated, which triggers the relaxation response and reduces stress.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A bolster underneath the backs of your knees in Savasana will help to support your lower back. You can also lie down over the bolster to create a backbend in a couple of different ways - with the bolster running parallel to the spine and head for a gentle chest opening or perpendicular underneath the middle of the back for a bigger backbend.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pigeon pose with a bolster underneath both hips will keep you grounded, so that you can really soften into the support beneath you. Child’s pose on top of a bolster has the same effect.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A bolster can also be used as a sitting cushion to support your meditation practice.</span></p>
<p><b>Yoga Blanket</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The warmth and comfort of a blanket will keep you cozy in restorative postures, especially Savasana. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A rolled </span><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/products/cotton-yoga-blanket-1?_pos=7&amp;_sid=0052ca563&amp;_ss=r"><span style="font-weight: 400;">blanket</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> can double as a mini bolster, to be placed under the back of your knees in Savasana, or underneath your back in the ways listed above for the bolster. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A folded blanket can also provide a little bit of height underneath your hips while you sit, or for seated postures such as Paschimottanasana (seated forward bend). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A blanket can also heat up your yoga practice - ever heard of blanket slides? To strengthen the hamstrings, set up as you would for bridge pose with a blanket under your feet. As you lift up into a glute bridge, you slide the blanket out and in to strengthen the backs of your legs. To strengthen the inner thighs, stand on the blanket with your hands on the floor (or blocks) and slide your legs out wide and then back in.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are so many ways for you to use your yoga props to support your practice, so get creative and enjoy! Namaste. </span></p>
<img alt="" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/KMPreview-18_copy_medium.jpg?v=1585847950" style="float: left; margin-right: 5px;"><meta charset="utf-8"><span class="il"><strong>About the author</strong><span> <br></span>Kate</span><span> Gillespie is a Vancouver based yoga teacher and teacher trainer. She is passionate about intelligent sequencing, creative prop work, hands-on adjustments, and connecting with her students. You can find her in local Vancouver studios, leading retreats and teacher trainings around the world. Catch her online at </span><a href="http://www.kategillespie.ca/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.kategillespie.ca&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1585930321531000&amp;usg=AFQjCNF-84s_g0kby4jdduc7lY51rgzszw" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.kategillespie.ca</a><span> or </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/kategillespieyoga/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@kategillespieyoga</a><span> on Instagram. </span><br> <meta charset="utf-8">]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/meditation-101</id>
    <published>2020-04-06T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-22T16:05:17-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/meditation-101"/>
    <title>Meditation 101 with Amanda Vitaro</title>
    <author>
      <name>Amanda Vitaro</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">Now, more than ever, is the time to pause, recenter and reset. Meditation<span> has been seen to reduce levels of stress, increase calmness and enhance one's awareness of self. However, it can take practice. Read on for an easy step-by-step guide on how you can start meditating. </span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/meditation-101">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Even just the thought of starting a meditation practice can be intimidating; How? Where? Why? What’s the point? It can be difficult getting used to relaxing, being unstimulated by external sources, and being “unproductive” during this time of social distancing however a meditation practice can be one of the most stimulating, productive parts of your day. When we sit down to meditate, we are taking time to clean out and polish the inside of our vessel (our body). We clear through the congestion that is caused by the thinking mind, bringing us into a more balanced and even internal energy. Through doing this, we can start to know ourselves and our truth (aka our soul) on a much deeper level. When we get to know our truth in this way, we are able to gain access to the engine that drives our life.</p>
<p>The purpose of meditation is to heal inner wounds, find a more centred energy, but also to cultivate a deep understanding of our truth and essence. When we meditate, we provide ourselves with the opportunity to wake up, to stop living in an unconscious state where our conditioning is the motivation behind our behaviours, words, thoughts, and actions. Through meditation, we can begin to live fully, balanced and empowered by our truth. </p>
<p><b>Step 1. Find a guide/teacher</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The best way to start a meditation practice is to find a teacher or a guided meditation to lead you through the process. Guided meditations will help you stay focused and provide you with tools and techniques to carry out a meditation practice for an extended period of time. When it comes to guided meditations, there are tons of content available in the form of online videos, apps, and books. Explore with different guides and styles and work with what resonates with you. It might take a few tries until you find this, but don’t stop until you do. There is a guide/style for everyone.</span></p>
<p><b>Step 2. Create your space </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second step? Create your meditation space. This can start off by just having a comfy seat to sit on such as a cushion or blanket (I have always used a </span><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/mod-meditation-cushion-zabuton"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mod Cushion and Zabuton sit set</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">). It is very important that you are as comfortable as possible when you meditate as it is very difficult to meditate in an uncomfortable body. Make sure this is a space that is generally quiet and feels safe for you. Create a calming ambience with candles, incense or essential oils, crystals, pictures of spiritual figures or loved ones, and anything else that inspires you. </span></p>
<p><b>Step 3. Establish a schedule</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Create a “loose” meditation schedule for yourself. You will hear most people say that you have to meditate first thing in the morning. While I personally find I benefit from this as it helps to set the stage for my day, there is no need to put this pressure on yourself when first starting out. Pick a length of time that you can commit to without worrying about having a strict meditation schedule. Plan for at least 20 minutes each day. While this sounds like a lot, it does take a while for one to calm the body and mind before you can comfortably enter a meditation. Start with 20 and allow your meditations to naturally increase over time. Eventually, play around with meditating at different times of the day to see how it affects you throughout your day. Start to understand what brings you the most benefit, then commit to a time. Remember, every day is different than the next so falling off schedule is normal. The key thing is to get your practice in each day.</span></p>
<p><b>Step 4. Explore and learn different techniques.</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Prathyahara (withdrawing of senses, focusing inward), Pranayama (breath work), mantra repetition, Japa (using mala beads) are just a few meditation techniques one can try. Play with all the different techniques that are out there and explore how they benefit you and your inner energy. You will eventually build a toolbox of techniques with different purposes that you will learn to use depending on the day and your energetic state. A great book to learning and exploring techniques is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meditation for the Love of</span></i><em><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I</span></em><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>t </em>by Sally Kempton.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just like life, your meditation practice will be different each day. At one end of the spectrum, some days you might have psychedelic, out of body experiences, and others you may sit down, close your eyes, and fall asleep. We need to be ok with this and know whatever happens during our meditation practice is supposed to happen. There is no end goal here, no finish line; you will find the benefits of your practice slowly seeping into your daily life. Our practice should be a time to retreat, to go within, and reconnect. To come back to what matters, the heart and truth of life.  Rid yourself of all expectations before you practice, and allow it to unfold as it may. </span></p>
<p style="float: left;"><span><strong><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/IMG_7307_medium.png?v=1585589668" style="float: left;">  </strong></span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: left;">Amanda Vitaro is a meditation guide, vinyasa  teacher, and reiki healer who is dedicated to guiding others to live the most beautiful, fulfilling life possible. Through movement and meditation she guides students into the innermost workings of themselves to connect deeply, and heal. After completing two pilgrimages in India, Amanda brings to her sessions ancient mysticism and wisdom, and combines it with the modern practical world. You can find her on Instagram <a href="https://www.instagram.com/amandavitaro/">@amandavitaro</a>   </p>
<p><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em><span size="6">*Please note that Halfmoon content is provided for informational purposes only and is not intended as medical advice, or as a substitute for the medical advice of a physician.</span></em></span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/crystal-healing</id>
    <published>2019-12-06T08:23:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-24T11:36:55-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/crystal-healing"/>
    <title>Crystal Healing with Mara Branscombe</title>
    <author>
      <name>Taelor Gray</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Historically, cultures all over the world have used crystals as a source of healing, clearing energy, and transforming both physical and spiritual states. Recently, there has been a resurgence of crystal healing and a growing movement of people discovering how crystals can positively enhance wellness in body, mind, and spirit.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/crystal-healing">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><b></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Historically, cultures all over the world have used crystals as a source of healing, clearing energy, and transforming both physical and spiritual states. Recently, there has been a resurgence of crystal healing and a growing movement of people discovering how crystals can positively enhance wellness in body, mind, and spirit.</span></p>
<p><b>How does Crystal Healing Work?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even though you cannot necessarily see or even feel it, the cells inside your body and the energy of crystals contain their own unique vibrations and energy. Imagine how a magnet works, it repels and attracts energy, and this is also how it is thought that healing crystals work. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you hold a crystal in your hand, or place it over an area in your body, you respond in a way that you may or may not feel. Crystals contain the mineral silicon dioxide and so do our human bodies, therefore we are naturally receptive to the vibration of these stone’s healing power. The results can be anything from relaxing the nervous system, to energizing the whole body and clearing out negative energy — all depending on the alchemy of the crystal.</span></p>
<p><b>How Do You Work With Crystals?</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are so many ways in which I use crystals to heal, harmonize and generate positive energy in my life. I invite you to use them in whichever way serves you best. Here are some of my favourites:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">- Wearing crystals <br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">- Placing crystals on specific body parts<br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">- Place them on my altar, in my home, office, etc.<br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">- Hold crystals while meditating<br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">- Putting crystals under my pillow while sleeping</span></p>
<p><b>Some Crystals and Their Healing Properties</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Rose Quartz: Known as the love stone — it’s pink colour is associated with the heart and unconditional love towards self, others, and the world. It can support your rising self esteem, while balancing your heart chakra and it is known to soothe heart aches. It’s healing properties include: improving circulation, lowering blood pressure, releasing tension, and deep emotional healing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clear Quartz: Known as the spirit stone and the master healer — it’s physical qualities increase the flow of energy in the body. Clear quartz increases perception, awareness, and stimulates both brain and immune systems. It is also known to be a conduit to expand consciousness and prayers from the spirit world to the physical world. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amethyst: Known as the manifestation stone — it’s stunning purple shimmer is associated with calming the nervous system, balancing hormones, relieving headaches and getting a good night’s sleep. Place amethyst under your pillow to rest deeply, and awaken ready to create and manifest your life.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tiger’s Eye: Known as the shapeshifter — this stone holds the essence of courage and motivation. Tiger’s Eye can support the shift of fear or toxic thinking into self confidence and courage. It can also support your mental capacity and allow you to stay truly focused on your passion in life. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jade: Known as the lucky charm stone - this stone has a lush green finish that reflects the natural elements in nature. Jade is a symbol for growth and vitality promoting self-sufficiency. It instills a sense of prosperity and harmony, soothing the mind and releasing stress. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In our fast paced, technological world, crystals can support our minds, bodies, and spirits in a highly effective and healing way. As you choose your stones, you will also begin to awaken your intuition and tap into your higher self as it can guide you into which stone is right for you. Crystal healing is for all ages and stages of life — from children to teens to mid life, to our elders, we can all benefit from raising up our frequency to that of mother earth’s finest stones. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Enjoy your crystal healing journey.</span></p>
<img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0040/3098/8386/files/MaraBio_cb296538-a122-4d52-a9ab-bcc8a9cff4fa.jpg?v=1570135715" style="margin-right: 20px; float: left;">
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span>In her yoga teachings, Mara weaves together her background as a dance artist, her practice in the shamanic tradition, and her twenty years of experience on her mat – naturally what arises is a fluid, earthy, full bodied practice. Currently, Mara hosts international yoga retreats, </span><span>offers online courses, fuses yoga and corporate leadership to executive teams, teaches professional athletes and artists, mentors yoga teachers and teaches classes/workshops. Mara is a mother of two in Vancouver, BC. Find out more about Mara on her website at </span><a href="http://www.marabranscombe.com/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.marabranscombe.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1544229816063000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHUXOm4zD-HFCiTRyjPv7pVCDuCCg" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.marabranscombe.com</a><span>. </span></span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>Please note that Halfmoon content is provided for informational purposes only and is not intended as medical advice, or as a substitute for the medical advice of a physician. </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/embodying-gratitude</id>
    <published>2019-10-09T08:30:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T15:32:25-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/embodying-gratitude"/>
    <title>Embodying Gratitude with Jessica Screeton</title>
    <author>
      <name>Taelor Gray</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>The holidays can be a busy time with all of the added social gatherings, meals and changes in routine. Here are a few simple ways to give love and thanks to yourself and others this season and help avoid</span><span> burnout.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/embodying-gratitude">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The holidays can be a busy time with all of the added social gatherings, meals and changes in routine. Here are a few simple ways to give love and thanks to yourself and others this season and help avoid burnout. </span></p>
<p><strong>THANK AND HONOUR YOURSELF + YOUR BODY </strong></p>
<p>It all begins with the Self. Practicing being kind, loving and accepting of yourself has a profound impact on everything in your life. Many of us are quick to dismiss the importance of showing ourselves the same TLC we offer others. I love to start a timer for a few minutes in the morning for meditation. Taking a nap, a bath, lighting a candle, cooking a meal, having a fire with my husband, going for a walk with my son, taking a Kundalini yoga class, catching up with friends, having deep, meaningful conversations are some of my go-to’s to recharge and replenish. You’ll know what self-care feels nourishing to you! Your body will thank you and you will be able to show up better for yourself and others as a result.</p>
<p><strong>ACTS OF KINDNESS </strong></p>
<p>Big or small, an act of kindness is such a quick way to positively shift the energy in a situation. When you give with zero expectations, something magical happens. First, you significantly raise the vibration around you with your intention of service and love. Second, it feels really good to pay it forward. Tune into how you feel after performing a simple act of kindness—it’s a win, win! </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The simplest way to find an opportunity to pay it forward is to slow down and be in the present moment. In that space, you can clearly see where your kindness is needed. </span></p>
<p><strong>AFFIRM WHAT YOU ALREADY HAVE </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Take a look around at all of the abundance in your life. For starters, you are inherently beautiful vessel as a human being. The relationships in your life, the things that light you up, the love that you give and receive, a roof over your head, the food in your belly, and the list goes on. Expressing gratitude in a journal, in your head or out loud are all ways that you can affirm something. This affirms what you already have and will actually end up attracting and inviting more abundance into your life as a result. My favourite way to start the day is by saying “Thank you for the gift of another day. Today is going to be an amazing day!”. </span><br><br></p>
<img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/Jess-7_3_large.jpg?v=1568654964" style="float: left; margin: 5px;" width="302" height="231">
<p><span><strong>Jessica Screeton</strong> is a spiritual mentor and psychic medium who runs a mentorship program specializing in helping people align with their soul's purpose. Jess is passionate about teaching basic spiritual practices, intuitive development and giving step-by-step tools to manifest one's dream life. She lives just outside of Vancouver, BC with her husband, Phill, and their son, River. When she's not serving clients, she enjoys spending time with family and friends, taking a kundalini yoga class + creating. </span>You can find Jessica on instagram (@jessicascreeton) or on her website (www.jessicascreeton.com).</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/props-for-a-better-posture</id>
    <published>2019-09-26T08:30:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-22T16:06:11-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/props-for-a-better-posture"/>
    <title>Props for a Better Posture</title>
    <author>
      <name>Taelor Gray</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>Everyday activities like sitting at a desk, staring at a computer, hunching over a cell phone or even holding a bag consistently on one side can cause stagnancy, stiffness and fatigue in the body. As habits build, poor posture can easily become second nature, causing back and neck pain and even damaging spinal structures.</span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>However, the main factors that affect posture are totally within our control, and aren’t difficult to change with consistent awareness. If you’re sitting at a desk for eight hours a day, the following tips will help support you in maintaining a better posture.<br></span></p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/props-for-a-better-posture">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over time, everyday activities like sitting at a desk, staring at a computer, hunching over a cell phone or even holding a bag consistently on one side can cause stagnancy, stiffness and fatigue in the body. As habits build, poor posture can easily become second nature, causing back and neck pain and even damaging spinal structures.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the main factors that affect posture are totally within our control, and aren’t difficult to change with consistent awareness. If you’re sitting at a desk for eight hours a day, the following tips will help support you in maintaining a better posture.</span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><b>1. Mini Cotton-Filled Cylindrical Bolster</b></p>
<p><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/mini.jpg?v=1564423808" style="float: none;"></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To support the lumbar spine at your desk or at home, place the mini-cylindrical bolster just behind the lower back. Giving yourself this support means that sitting up taller will feel easier on your spine, helping build core strength to support good posture.</span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><b>2. Linen Hot and Cold Therapy Pillow</b></span></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/linen.jpg?v=1564426709" style="float: none;"></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Slouching over a keyboard for hours is tough on the shoulders. The more tension is held in the neck and shoulders, the more challenging it is to get rid of. Placing the Hot and Cold Therapy Pillow across the back of your shoulders will provide a welcome release for muscle tension -- alternate between hot and cold for optimal release!</span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><b>3. Natural Rubber Massage Peanut</b></span></p>
<img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/massage_c6ff80b8-00d0-4b7c-9f9d-d27986e548ed.jpg?v=1564426833" alt=""><br>
<p><b></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Small enough to carry around with you, this massage peanut is the perfect size and shape to massage muscles prone to tension along either side of the spine. As its name suggests, this massage ball is peanut shaped and designed to cradle the spine to relieve tension in the surrounding muscles with medium to firm pressure. Use by leaning into a wall or an office chair to provide relief where you need it most!</span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><b>4. Joy-a-Toes</b></span></p>
<img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/joyatoes.jpg?v=1564424905" alt=""><br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Good posture starts with the feet! Correct distribution of weight in our feet gives the body optimal postural alignment, creating a great foundation that helps the feet engage and recover. Wearing Joy-a-Toes for 15-20 minutes per day (increasing over time) helps realign the bones and soft tissue, stimulates circulation and increases flexibility and strength in the feet. It is important to work from the ground up to ensure posture is strong and maintainable.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I challenge you to incorporate the above into your daily practices as well as taking just a few minutes every hour to walk around, stretch out and get the blood flowing — this will do wonders for posture, as well as help relieve stiffness, soreness and tension in the body. In a world that can be so demanding, it is important that we take time for ourselves, care for our body and be mindful of what it is asking of us.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<div style="float: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/liv_large.jpeg?v=1564428457" style="float: left; margin-right: 10px;" width="273" height="273"></div>
<span><strong>Liv Law </strong>is a yoga and pilates teacher offering powerful, all-level classes. She teaches in Vancouver, and completed her initial 200 hour training in 2017 at Blue Osa in Costa Rica. She began practicing yoga in her early teens and continues to learn and be inspired every single day by classes she attend, students in her classes, and things that happen around her. Follow her on Instagram </span><a href="https://www.instagram.com/yogi_liv/?hl=en">@yogi_liv</a><span> and her website </span><a href="http://livlawyoga.com/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://livlawyoga.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1538001785663000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE9lecyttVy9nEGahAP-mqrTv1ngw" rel="noopener noreferrer">livlawyoga.com</a><span>!</span>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/harvest-moon-meditation-with-kellie-paroginog</id>
    <published>2019-09-13T09:37:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-13T09:37:22-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/harvest-moon-meditation-with-kellie-paroginog"/>
    <title>Harvest Moon Meditation with Kellie Paroginog</title>
    <author>
      <name>Taelor Gray</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8">
<p class="p1"><span>Throughout this meditation, we let go and start to cultivate new energy for the new season. We invite and accept transition and gain perspective, we notice what does no longer serve us and make room for what it is that we are truly seeking. </span></p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/harvest-moon-meditation-with-kellie-paroginog">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="p1">In this 30 minute meditation we are guided through a relaxing Yoga Nidra body meditation, followed by a Harvest Moon inspired visual meditation. The spiritual meaning behind the Harvest Moon is a cosmic reminder to release all that has been slowly building in the past months, in order to reset and start again. Are you ready to stand in your truth? The moon is asking us to assert ourselves, seeking balance and harmony as we move forward. </p>
<p class="p1">Throughout this meditation, we let go and start to cultivate new energy for the new season. We invite and accept transition and gain perspective, we notice what does no longer serve us and make room for what it is that we are truly seeking. </p>
<iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/679767848%3Fsecret_token%3Ds-iCUki&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&amp;visual=true"></iframe>
<p class="p1"> </p>
<br><meta charset="utf-8">
<p class="p1" style="float: left;"><strong><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/kellie_large.jpg?v=1568151741" style="float: left; margin: 10px;" width="278" height="304">Kellie Paroginog </strong> - This meditation was created by yoga and meditation teacher, Kellie Paroginog of Vancouver, Canada. To Kellie, Yoga is a place to get quiet, be still and listen within, so that ultimately we can hear our hearts longing and connect to ourselves and then others. Kellie believes and lives from a place of togetherness, she feels that by sharing Yoga and meditation, we can unite and become one.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/sound-bathing</id>
    <published>2019-09-10T08:30:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-09-10T08:30:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/sound-bathing"/>
    <title>Sound Bathing</title>
    <author>
      <name>Taelor Gray</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8"><span>Sound healing sessions sometimes known as sound baths, sound meditations, sound journeys or sound ceremonies, are all incredible spaces to receive the amazing benefits of working with sound to heal the body and mind. Whether this be with a skilled and trained facilitator or on your own with sacred instruments, like singing bowls, gongs, rattles, chimes or the voice, there are a wide variety of ways in which one can explore and help effectively free the body and mind of dis-ease, depression, anxiety, stress, or even physical discomfort and pain. Here, we will discuss what a sound healing can look like, how to participate in a session, and the many benefits of working with sound as medicine.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/sound-bathing">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“He who knows the secret of the sound, knows the mystery of the whole universe.” </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">-Hazrat Inayat Khan</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sound healing sessions sometimes known as sound baths, sound meditations, sound journeys or sound ceremonies, are all incredible spaces to receive the amazing benefits of working with sound to heal the body and mind. Whether this be with a skilled and trained facilitator or on your own with sacred instruments, like singing bowls, gongs, rattles, chimes or the voice, there are a wide variety of ways in which one can explore and help effectively free the body and mind of dis-ease, depression, anxiety, stress, or even physical discomfort and pain. Here, we will discuss what a sound healing can look like, how to participate in a session, and the many benefits of working with sound as medicine. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Often in sessions, participants bring cushions, blankets and mats to lay down and receive the sound bath for typically just over an hour. Laying down allows the body and mind to be in a deeply receptive state. From here, it is a good practice to have a moment to check in with yourself. What are you present with? During a sound session, emotions, memories, thoughts, triggers, or physical sensations may arise. All are valid and welcomed experiences and can inform the participant of any focal points the body is presenting. This is in a sense a language and a way to communicate and understand what the body is holding, often times subconsciously. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">One of the most important things to note when working with sound is it is as much about the external sounds coming in as it is about how the participant meets the sound or invites the sounds in with the whole body. The best way to receive the most benefit from any sound session experience is to stay open and curious about how the sounds move through the body. What memories or emotions do they bring up, what mental process or physical sensations arise? This is a practice of engaging the inner witness and deeply listening - the receptive side of sound healing. Each participant of a sound journey has a diverse number of experiences and NONE are wrong. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sound Medicine is an empowering way to continue on the path of inner awareness. It can take courage, effort and a bit of work to dive into the inner territory, but it can also be fun, playful and pleasurable. Whatever arises for you in the soundscape is perfect for you at the time. My closing invitation to you is to enjoy these beautiful soundscapes, dive deep in curiosity and awaken the receptive side of sound as medicine. </span></p>
<img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/ocianauthor.jpg?v=1564676399" style="float: left; margin: 10px;" width="272" height="272">
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Ocian Sound </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For more information, sessions, workshops, programs on this language of sound and other sound tools and recordings, visit my website at</span><a href="http://www.ociansound.com/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">www.ociansound.com</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. (@ociansound) </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/celebrating-our-community-30-years-30-mats</id>
    <published>2019-08-09T08:30:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-09T11:11:45-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/celebrating-our-community-30-years-30-mats"/>
    <title>Celebrating our Community — 30 Years, 30 Mats</title>
    <author>
      <name>Taelor Gray</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8">
<p>Our community is something we are very proud of at Halfmoon; we are so grateful to have the opportunity to give back. Thank you for all your support over the years, we appreciate each and every one of you!</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/celebrating-our-community-30-years-30-mats">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last month, we celebrated our 30 Year Anniversary! To honour this milestone we gave away 30 yoga mats to three deserving organizations. We were completely blown away by the amount of responses and amazing stories that were shared with us and we want to send out a big thank you to everyone who participated.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The recipients of our Anniversary Giveaway are three people who spread the healing power of yoga in their own communities. Congratulations to DeNel, Leslie and Julie — it is amazing what you are doing for the yoga community and this world as a whole. We are thrilled to be able to contribute to your work. Keep being YOU.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><b>DeNel — </b><b>Nova Scotia, Canada  </b></p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/denel1.jpg?v=1564432199" alt=""></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">DeNel teaches yoga and meditation to the residents of </span><a href="http://bonnyleafarm.ca/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bonny Lea Farm</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This rural residence is the home and workplace of adults living with varying physical and intellectual challenges. In a family-like setting, participants are taught by staff and volunteers. They learn self-respect, love one for another, dignity, integrity, productivity, and responsible community living. Yoga and meditation are one of their activities, and DeNel is their teacher. In addition to offering classes for the participants, DeNel gifts classes to the amazing caregivers who work tirelessly to allow the residents of Bonny Lea Farm the opportunity to live their lives fully. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><b>Julie — </b><b>Ontario, Canada</b></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/julie.jpg?v=1564431946" style="float: none;"></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Julie partners with an addiction recovery home to bring trauma informed sessions to mothers as well as their babies. By giving these mothers a place to practice, both mother and child, are able to experience gentle movements and soothing touch. In addition to her classes within the recovery center, Julie also facilitates yoga classes for the workers of the organization, helping them with the self care needed to continue with the amazing work they do. For Julie, more mats means more people can participate and she can continue to spread the wonderful benefits of yoga!</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><b>Leslie — </b><b>Indiana, USA </b></p>
<p><b><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/leslie.jpg?v=1564433273" alt=""></b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leslie is a Licensed Mental Health Counsellor who uses yoga and meditation to help people in recovery from addiction. The majority of her clients have no access to yoga due to financial reasons or lack of services in the area. Leslie has a very genuine, determined, and willing group of people in her Intensive Outpatient Group that are excited by the changes they are making with mindful awareness and increased mind body connection.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our community is something we are very proud of at Halfmoon; we are so grateful to have the opportunity to give back. Thank you for all your support over the years, we appreciate each and every one of you!</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/pura-vida</id>
    <published>2019-07-27T09:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-07-27T09:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/pura-vida"/>
    <title>Living Pura Vida</title>
    <author>
      <name>Taelor Gray</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>To embody Pura Vida means to move about your day in less of a hurry, allowing time to soak in the sweetness of your journey and to face each moment with optimism.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/pura-vida">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>Have you had the great pleasure of visiting Costa Rica? If so, allow me to transport you back, and if not, let me paint a picture — countless palm trees line never ending white sand beaches, the ocean is warm and inviting, and friendly locals sell coconuts while calling out “Pura Vida” as you stroll along.<br><br><span>Pura Vida is a term you will likely hear numerous times a day while in Costa Rica. It is used as a greeting to both friends and strangers alike, as the most common answer to ‘como estas’, or ‘how are you?’, and even in place of a goodbye when parting ways. Literally translated, Pura Vida means ‘pure life’; however, to local Costa Ricans it is so much more than that — it is a way of life. To embody Pura Vida means to move about your day in less of a hurry, allowing time to soak in the sweetness of your journey and to face each moment with optimism.</span><br><br><span>Yoga and meditation are both practises that embody the essence of Pura Vida. Whether you choose to practise in the comfort of your own home, or at your favourite studio, the act of stepping onto your mat allows you to slow down, hit pause, and exist in the present moment. </span><br><br><span>We live in an increasingly fast paced world, and are expected to be constantly moving forward towards our next goal. While having dreams and aspirations are absolutely necessary, it is equally as important to recognize and enjoy where you are currently. Yoga and meditation lovingly demand you to slow down physically, which gives your mind an opportunity to become still, creating space for you to just BE. <br></span><br><span>Hitting pause, decompressing and appreciating the simplicity of life is a daily practice here in Costa Rica. At sunset, families spill out onto the streets, watching as the sky transforms from blue to pink, and connect with their loved ones. This is exactly what Pura Vida is all about. <br></span><br><span>No need for coconuts or warm ocean swims, simply adopting a Pura Vida attitude can lead to the same happiness you feel while digging your toes into the sand. Whether you only have time for a few deep breaths or an hour long mindfulness practise, I encourage you to roll out your mat, sit quietly and witness your life transform! </span></p>
<p> </p>
<meta charset="utf-8"><img alt="Sally Rubin" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0040/3098/8386/files/sally_9a231deb-a99c-4901-9fac-2bc555a856af.jpg?v=1562866287" style="float: left; margin-right: 15px;" width="276" height="282">
<p class="p1"><strong>Sally Rubin </strong>says it wasn’t long into becoming a student of yoga 11 years ago that she felt the transformation it was bringing her and felt pulled to become a teacher herself. Her hope is to share all of the tools she has learned along her journey with as many people as possible so that others may be able to realize their potential to be truly happy and fulfilled. Sally is compassionate, supportive, grounded, genuine and hilarious. She currently spends her time in Central America, Canada and Bali, teaching public classes, workshops and teacher trainings, spreading her love of yoga and living the Pura Vida. <a href="https://www.instagram.com/sallyrubin/" target="_blank" title="Sally Rubin — Instagram" rel="noopener noreferrer">You can find Sally on instagram here</a> and <a href="https://www.sallyrubinyoga.com/" target="_blank" title="Sally Rubin" rel="noopener noreferrer">on her website here.</a></p>
<p class="p1"> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/travelling-yogi</id>
    <published>2019-06-27T09:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-06-27T09:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/travelling-yogi"/>
    <title>The Travelling Yogi</title>
    <author>
      <name>Taelor Gray</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Going</span><span> out of town but looking to keep up your yoga practice? We've got you covered! Check out our 5 "must have items" to travel with, no matter where you are </span><span>headed</span><span>.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/travelling-yogi">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span style="font-weight: 300;">As summer and travel plans take hold, it is easy for our regular self-care routines to slip. One of the great things about yoga is you can take it anywhere. Practicing on the go can be just what you need to cultivate presence and find balance during your time away. Here's our list of 5 "must haves" to help you keep up with your self-care no matter where you are headed!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/b-mat-traveller/products/b-mat-traveller-2mm?variant=19445570404470" target="_blank" title="BMat Traveller" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/travelmat_43fc94c8-4a2d-4af5-8949-b8f352b6da2f.jpg?v=1561491314" alt="BMat Traveller"></a></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/b-mat-traveller/products/b-mat-traveller-2mm?variant=19445570404470" target="_blank" title="BMat Traveller" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>B Mat Traveller</b></a><span> - </span><span>With a thinner construction, 2mm, and lightweight design, the B MAT® Traveller is designed for the on-the-go yogi. It easily folds to fit into your suitcase, backpack or overnight bag. </span><span>There’s no reason to leave it at home!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/straps/products/yoga-mat-strap-organic?variant=19442974752886" target="_blank" title="Carry Mat Strap" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 300;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/carrymatstrap.jpg?v=1561489201" alt="Mat Carry Strap"></span></a></p>
<meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: left;"><b><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/straps/products/yoga-mat-strap-organic?variant=19442974752886" target="_blank" title="Mat Carry Strap" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Mat Carry Strap</a><span style="font-weight: 300;"><span> </span>-<span> </span></span><span style="font-weight: 300;">Simply brilliant and brilliantly simple, this versatile strap fits any yoga mat for easy transporting, no bag required. When you get to class it doubles as a yoga strap. No complicated buckles—just thoughtful, functional design.</span></b></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 300;"><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/blankets/products/cotton-yoga-blanket-beach-stripe?variant=21271504191548" target="_blank" title="Cotton Yoga Blanket Beach Stripe" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/yogablanket.jpg?v=1561491262" alt="Cotton Yoga Blanket Beach Stripe"></a></span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: left;"><b><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/blankets/products/cotton-yoga-blanket-beach-stripe?variant=21271504191548" target="_blank" title="Cotton Yoga Blanket Beach Stripe" rel="noopener noreferrer">Cotton Yoga Blanket Beach Stripe</a> </b><span style="font-weight: 300;">- A functional yoga prop that doubles as your outdoor beach blanket. Roll it like a bolster, fold it for seated poses or shoulder stand, and use it as a cozy cover during your favourite festival. This multi-functional striped blanket is handw</span><span style="font-weight: 300;">oven with flat selvage edges, it folds flat and stacks evenly making it the yoga blanket of choice for travel.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/natural-cork-massage-ball-trio?variant=19445119778934" target="_blank" title="Natural Cork Massage Balls" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 300;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/MassageTrio.jpg?v=1561489285" alt="Massage Ball Trio"></span></a></p>
<meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8">
<p><b><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/natural-cork-massage-ball-trio?variant=19445119778934" target="_blank" title="Natural Cork Massage Balls" rel="noopener noreferrer">Natural Cork Massage Ball Trio</a> </b>- Perfect for relieving tension as you travel! Massage balls relieve pain, increase circulation and calm your nervous system. Lean into a wall, chair or the floor to create just the right pressure in those hard-to-reach spots. Experiment to find the exact pressure you’re looking for or roll the matching massage balls on either side of your spine for balanced release. </p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/toes.jpg?v=1561492950" alt="Joy a Toes"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><b><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/products/joy-a-toes" target="_blank" title="Joy a Toes" rel="noopener noreferrer">Joy-a-Toes</a> </b><span>- </span><span>Give your toes some breathing room. At times, travel can call for a lot of walking and go, go, go — use Joy-a-Toes to r</span>evitalize your tired, hardworking feet! Made from a soft, comfortable gel, these are the most versatile toe spreaders available. Wear during your practice, or in loose-fitting footwear.</p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/how-to-use-your-massage-tools</id>
    <published>2019-06-06T10:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-06-06T10:00:28-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/how-to-use-your-massage-tools"/>
    <title>Make Massage Part of your Wellness Practice</title>
    <author>
      <name>Amanda Vitaro</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>We’ve got quite the massage collection to roll out any problem areas that have been affecting your body. Find the tool that will help your needs the most, from massaging out large muscle groups to hard-to-reach areas, we got you covered!</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/how-to-use-your-massage-tools">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Find the massage tools that give your body what it needs the most! Whether you're looking to massage out large muscle groups or smaller hard-to-reach areas, the <a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage">Massage Collection</a> has got you covered. Read on to learn our favourite ways to use each tool.</span></p>
<br>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/natural-rubber-massage-peanut?variant=21296257990716" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Natural Rubber Massage Peanut</b></a></p>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/natural-rubber-massage-peanut?variant=21296257990716" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/DSC_8949_1200x600_5f7425c3-93b1-4a70-bb61-48417b5151cc_1024x1024.jpg?v=1552678607" alt=""></b></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/natural-rubber-massage-peanut?variant=21296257990716">Natural Rubber Massage Peanut</a> offers medium to firm pressure that can help improve your circulation and relieve muscle tension. This is a great tool to massage your spine. Lean the top of your spine into the massage peanut and roll the peanut up and down, massaging your back along a wall, chair or the floor. This motion allows the tightness in your muscles around your spine to relax and can improve your range of motion. It also reduce headaches that may have been caused by tension held along your spine.  </span></p>
<br>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/jumbo-natural-rubber-massage-ball?variant=21296279912508"><b>Jumbo Natural Rubber Ball</b></a></p>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/jumbo-natural-rubber-massage-ball?variant=21296279912508"><b><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/DSC_9534_1200x600_1024x1024.jpg?v=1552678856" alt=""></b></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/jumbo-natural-rubber-massage-ball?variant=21296279912508">Jumbo Natural Rubber Massage Ball</a> is great to roll out larger muscles such as your back, hips, buttocks and legs. With medium to firm pressure, this jumbo rubber ball can release tight muscles, improve your range of motion, improve circulation and enhance joint movement. Our favourite way to massage the body with this tool is to lean the outside of the thigh on the ball while rolling along the floor. This movement softens the thigh muscles and massages the IT band — a difficult spot to stretch.  </span></p>
<br>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/natural-cork-massage-ball-trio?variant=19445119778934"><b>Natural Cork Massage Ball</b></a></p>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/natural-cork-massage-ball-trio?variant=19445119778934"><b><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/CorkMassageInUse3_1200x600_1024x1024.jpg?v=1552679031" alt=""></b></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The<a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/natural-cork-massage-ball-trio?variant=19445119778934"> Natural Cork Massage Ball Trio </a> comes with two 75mm balls and one 50mm ball for those hard-to-reach areas. These cork balls offer firm pressure that can calm your nervous system and relieve tension. One area this is often overlooked are the inner thighs. Laying on the floor, place the 75mm near the top of the knee. Slowly roll downwards along the ball to relieve any pain or tension. Experiment with different sizes and amounts if pressure. The 50mm ball may be able to reach some target areas that the 75mm ball cannot find. </span></p>
<br>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/massage-balls?variant=19442701172854"><b>Massage Balls</b></a></p>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/massage-balls?variant=19442701172854"><b><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/2018_02_02_HMY_lifestyle_2076_1200x600_1024x1024.jpg?v=1552679190" alt=""></b></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These <a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/massage-balls?variant=19442701172854">Massage Balls</a> were made to stimulate energetic flow and reflexology points while releasing the tension in your muscles. One popular use is to place both balls under the back of your head on either side of the spine while laying on the floor or wall. Controlling the pressure applied into the massage balls, start to roll the balls down your neck. Massaging your neck like this can release tension that has been held from long days of sitting at a desk.</span></p>
<br>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/natural-cork-massage-roller?variant=21574620610620"><b>Natural Cork Massage Roller</b></a></p>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/natural-cork-massage-roller?variant=21574620610620"><b><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/DSC_8884_1200x600_1024x1024.jpg?v=1552680511" alt=""></b></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The<a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/natural-cork-massage-roller?variant=21574620610620"> Natural Cork Massage Roller </a>is an amazing healing tool that helps release toxins, improve circulation, enhance joint movement and relieve pain. This versatile tool is not only great for rolling out big muscles groups, but can roll out the wrist, hand and foot. One way we love to use this Massage Roller is for the soles of the feet. Placing the roller on the floor, add pressure into your foot to where it feels comfortable. Roll back and forth to relieve the tension in the arch and ball of the foot. </span></p>
<br>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/foam-roller-18?variant=19444041810038"><b>Foam Roller - 18”</b></a></p>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/foam-roller-18?variant=19444041810038"><b><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/InUse1_1200x600_1024x1024.jpg?v=1552682378" alt=""></b></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This <a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage/products/foam-roller-18?variant=19444041810038">foam roller</a> is a massage therapist, acupressure specialist and yoga prop all in one! The foam roller can target and massage out pain in larger muscle groups that have accumulated tightness. Place your upper thigh onto the foam roller, add pressure, and roll your thigh upwards along the roller to release deep tissues while strengthening your core. </span></p>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Explore the <a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Massage Collection</a> and shop all our tools <a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/massage" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>!</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/garden-of-love-meditation-with-connor-burns</id>
    <published>2019-05-29T00:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-05-29T13:18:36-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/garden-of-love-meditation-with-connor-burns"/>
    <title>Garden of Love Meditation with Connor Burns</title>
    <author>
      <name>Amanda Vitaro</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>In this peaceful 24 minute meditation we are guided through a relaxing body meditation, followed by a creative visual meditation in which we liken our day-to-day intentions to that of a vast beautiful garden.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/garden-of-love-meditation-with-connor-burns">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>In this peaceful 24 minute meditation we are guided through a relaxing body meditation, followed by a creative visual meditation in which we liken our day-to-day intentions to that of a vast beautiful garden.</p>
<p>As we walk quietly through our "Garden of Love", we begin to notice the first signs of life brought on by the energy of spring. This is a place where we can cultivate aspects of good in our life. From the colourful petals of forgiveness, to the refreshing scent of love lingering in the air —What seeds would you like to see bloom? Take time to uproot anything that is no longer supporting the overall growth of your garden and your life. Experience deep gratitude for this new life that we have mindfully planted into the soil. </p>
<p><iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/614859420&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true"></iframe>  </p>
<div style="float: left;">
<img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/ConnorBio.jpg?v=1541722672" style="margin-right: 20px; float: left;" width="198" height="238"><strong>Connor Burns</strong>' passion for self-inquiry finds a peaceful home in the unification of ancient teachings and new age science. Dedicated to creating a safe and sacred space for the individual to re-embrace the collective Soul is at the forefront of Connors commitment. In each breath we will move inward towards eternal love and together we discover the tranquil universe within and the stillness available with each moment.<br><br>Connor has certifications with Yoga Alliance, Moment Meditation™. <br><br>Connect with Connor through his <a href="https://www.connorburns.ca/">website</a> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/_cmburns/">instagram</a>. </div>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p><br><br><br><br></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/pre-surf-yoga-routine</id>
    <published>2019-05-20T22:30:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-05-20T22:30:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/pre-surf-yoga-routine"/>
    <title>Yoga Flow for Surfing</title>
    <author>
      <name>Claire Lester</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>What better way to warm up before you hit the waves than with a yoga flow? Get in touch with the earth and the ocean before your surf session with this sequence of energizing postures.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/pre-surf-yoga-routine">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>What better way to warm up before you hit the waves than with a yoga flow? Get in touch with the earth and the ocean before your surf session with this sequence of energizing postures.</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ob1XkE3bAv4" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Set up your <strong><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/mats">yoga mat</a></strong> or <strong><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/blankets/products/cotton-yoga-blanket-beach-stripe?variant=21271504191548">beach blanket</a></strong> and follow these steps to get into the flow of the elements around you. These poses will help to warm up your shoulders and strengthen your legs before paddling out and riding the surf.</p>
<p><strong>1. Side Bends<br></strong>Starting with your feet together, inhale both arms above your head. Clasp your hands together and let both fingers point towards the sky. Lean your upper body to the right, and keep your shoulders away from your ears. Inhale back to center and exhale to bend your upper body to the left side. Repeat as many times as you like to open up the side body and tune into your breath.</p>
<p><strong>2. Shoulder Stretch<br></strong>Clasp your hands together behind your back and roll your shoulders back as you reach down through your arms. Poses that stretch and warm up the shoulders and chest are a good way to prepare for paddling and popping up onto your board.</p>
<p><strong>3. Sun Salutation<br></strong>Release your hands, bend at the hips and bring your body into a forward fold. Let your head hang towards the ground. Inhale and lift your chest, keeping your back flat with your hands on your knees or shins. Exhale, forward fold again. Plant your hands into the ground and step back into a plank. Roll forward onto your toes and lower your body towards the earth — chaturanga. Peel your upper body up and un-tuck your toes coming into full cobra pose. Tuck your toes, pull your hips up and move into your first downward dog. Repeat 3-4 vinyasas to strengthen your core and continue to prep your arms and shoulders for paddling and pop-ups.</p>
<p><strong>4. Warrior II<br></strong>From downward dog, bring your right foot in between your hands and rotate your back foot at a 90 degree angle. Bend into your front leg until your knee is slightly over the ankle, keep your back leg straight and bring both arms away from your shoulders and parallel to your ground. Take a moment to focus on your core, strengthen your legs and balance. This pose will get you ready to stay on your board once you are up and riding waves.</p>
<p><strong>5. Exalted Warrior<br></strong>From warrior II pose, place your back hand on the back of your thigh as you flip your front palm upwards and reach towards the sky. Lift and lengthen your spine as you gaze up towards your hand. Feel the opening in your side body and stay strong in both legs to build heat and increase blood flow.</p>
<p><strong>6. Side Angle<br></strong>From exalted warrior, lower your front elbow above your knee. Reach your back arm above your head with your palm facing down, creating space between your shoulder and your ear. This pose emphasizes shoulder stability to prepare for paddling and popping up. Keep your legs and core strong here to avoid dumping into your shoulder.</p>
<p><strong>7. Tree Pose<br></strong>To practice balance and focus before you do it on your board, move into tree pose. Standing with your feet together, transfer your weight onto one foot and plant it firmly into the ground. Bend your other leg, and bring your knee out to the side and place the sole of your foot above the standing knee. Feel free to place the sole of your foot below the knee if your hips are feeling tight. As you find your balance, bring your hands to heart center.</p>
<p><strong>8. Wild Thing<br></strong>After doing both sides of your tree pose, make your way to downward dog. Lift your left leg towards the sky to come into three-legged dog. Transfer your weight onto your right hand, roll onto the outer edge of your right foot. With your left leg lifted, bend at the knee and step your left foot back, placing your toes on the floor. From here, lift your hips higher and sweep your left hand over your head. Make sure to do this on the other side as well to warm up both arms and shoulders.</p>
<p><strong>9. Child’s Pose<br></strong>From wild thing, come back to down dog. Drop your knees wide while keeping your feet together and sit back on your heels. Relax your forehead into the earth and exhale. Bring your attention to your breath as it moves in and out of your body. This mind/body connection will help prepare you for the waves ahead.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/yoga-sequence-for-renewal-with-nina-konjinius</id>
    <published>2019-05-13T13:47:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-05-17T14:56:03-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/yoga-sequence-for-renewal-with-nina-konjinius"/>
    <title>Yoga Sequence for Spring by Nina Konjini</title>
    <author>
      <name>Claire Lester</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Spring is an invitation to shake off any residual heaviness you may be carrying. It’s an awakening from the dull and possibly gloomy winter months to step into fresh new possibilities.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/yoga-sequence-for-renewal-with-nina-konjinius">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spring is an invitation to shake off any residual heaviness you may be carrying. It’s an awakening from the dull and possibly gloomy winter months to step into fresh new possibilities. Spring brings colour and life back in to our lives and invites us to shift from stagnation to change and transformation. Spring reflects all the ways in which we have the potential to start over.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let this beginner yoga practice clear out any congestion you might be feeling energetically, emotionally and physically. Let the breath be fluid and rhythmic throughout this dynamic practice. Take any variations you might need, and allow this practice to be equally energizing and restorative.</span> </p>
<p><b>Mountain (Tadasana)<br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/IMG_8307_1200x600_2048x2048.jpg?v=1555973367" alt=""></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Standing at the top of your mat, keep your feet hip distance apart and parallel. Gently close your eyes or drop your gaze down. Take a deep inhale through your nose and exhale slowly through your mouth, making your exhalation vocal. Send your breath to all the spaces in your body that might need attention.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Notice any sensations you might be experiencing at this moment. Check in energetically, notice how you feel on a scale of 1-10. Finally, tune into your thoughts, ideas, plans you might be making, expectations you may have, with the invitation to cast them all aside for the rest of this practice. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Find 7-10 breaths in your Tadasana</span> </p>
<p><b>Crescent Lunge + Twist  <br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/IMG_8354_1200x800_2048x2048.jpg?v=1555973393" alt=""></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Root down into your right foot and take a step back with your left leg. Staying on the ball of that foot, find a bend in your front knee, aligning it with your heel. As you extend your back leg, imagine pressing it against a wall. Soften the shoulders down, pull your shoulder blades together and lift your heart forward and up. Take a deep inhale as you reach the arms up and find a twist towards the right side, arms extended. Gently gaze over your back shoulder. Inhale bring the arms back, exhale and find the twist. Repeat 4 more times.</span> </p>
<p><b>Revolved Chair (Parivritta Utkatasana)<br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/IMG_8371_1200x800_2048x2048.jpg?v=1555973430" alt=""></b>Bring your hands to h<span style="font-weight: 400;">eart centre and slowly draw your left foot forward to meet your right. Align your knees, keep your shoulders stacked and continue to press your palms into one another. Make sure your knees and hips are parallel here. Soften into this the intensity. Find length in your spine as you reach through the crown of your head and explore a deeper twist on your exhale. Stay here for 3-5 breaths.</span> </p>
<p><b>Forward Fold (Uttanasana)<br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/IMG_8432_1200x800_2048x2048.jpg?v=1555973457" alt=""></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">On your next inhale, reach your arms up and exhale to find your forward fold. Soften your neck and shoulders. A slight bend in your knees will allow your belly to rest on your thighs to release tension in the lower back. As your feet root down, lift the toes up to activate the legs, then release them back down to your mat. Your fingertips can be on a block or touching the earth. Close your eyes and stay here for 5-10 breaths.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Inhale reach your arms up coming back to your Tadasana, and exhale hands to heart centre. With your eyes closed, pause here. Reconnect with your breath. Feel the expansion around your heart as you inhale, lifting your heart up. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Repeat these 3 poses on the other side. </span></p>
<p><b>Downward Facing Dog (Adho Mukha Svanasana) <br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/IMG_8468_1200x800_2048x2048.jpg?v=1555973484" alt=""></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">From Tadasana, inhale your arms above you and exhale, bending at the hips into your forward fold. Root your hands into the mat with your fingers spread wide. From here, step back into your downward facing dog. Feel free to bend your knees here, sending your sit bones up and back. Release the weight of your head and keep your shoulders square in this pose.</span> </p>
<p><b>Lord of the Fishes (Matsyendrasana)<br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/IMG_8480_1200x800_2048x2048.jpg?v=1555973507" alt=""></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">From a seated position, extend both legs out in front of you. Bend your right leg and place your foot on the outside of your left knee. Place your right hand behind you, tenting your fingers and find length in your spine. As you inhale, reach up with your left hand and exhale into your twist. Place your left elbow against your knee, or hold onto your thigh. Allow your inhales to lift your heart forward, emanating through your rib cage. Close your eyes, reach upwards through the crown of your head, and keep your chin parallel to the earth. Stay here for 7-10 breaths. On your exhale come back to centre and take a counter pose if you need. Do the same thing on the other side.</span></p>
<p><b>Bridge (Setu Bandha Sarvangasana)<br></b><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/IMG_8516_2048x2048.jpg?v=1556906009" alt="">Laying on your back, place the soles of your feet hip distance apart. On your inhale, press into your feet to lift your hips up. Pull your shoulder blades together and interlace your fingers behind your back. Soften your jaw and check in with your exhale. Activate your legs by imagining a block between your knees and lift your heart towards the sky. Stay here for 5-10 smooth and steady breaths. Release your fingers and bring the hips back down to the mat with control.</span></p>
<p><b>Windshield Wipers with a Twist<br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/IMG_8559_1200x800_2048x2048.jpg?v=1555973554" alt=""></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">With your knees still bent, take your feet as wide as your mat and gently bring your knees together. Grab opposite elbows in front of you. As you let both knees fall over to the left, take your arms, shoulders, and elbows to the right. Stay here for a few breaths, and switch sides, taking the knees to the right and the upper body over the left. Repeat as many times as you like and stay on each side as long as you need.</span></p>
<p><b>Corpse Pose (Savasana)<br><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/IMG_8575_1200x800_2048x2048.jpg?v=1555973575" alt=""></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Take a moment to get yourself as comfortable as possible. Lay on your back, take your feet as wide as your mat and palms facing up. Feel free to support your neck and knees with a bolster or a blanket. Take a deep inhale, filling up your lungs and your belly and then exhale with a deep sigh. Let your entire weight anchor into the earth. Soften around your eyes, gently part your lips, rest your tongue down. Let your breath be effortless and smooth. Savasana is an invitation to let go of all the things that no longer serve us, old stories, patterns, behaviours and thoughts. Releasing fully, in order to receive.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Allow your body to fully receive the benefits of your efforts and your practice. Stay in your Savasana for 5-10 minutes. Slowly bring your attention and your awareness back to the space, the sounds and your sensations. Take a conscious breath in. Gently find some movement into your fingertips and your toes. Start to rock your head from side to side. Keeping your eyes closed, roll over to one side into a fetal position for a few breaths, in stillness and in gratitude. Gently press into your hands as you find a comfortable seat. Bring your palms together in front of your heart. Notice here, if you feel differently —physically, energetically, or in your thoughts. Take a deep breath in to fill your lungs and your belly and exhale slowly.</span> </p>
<p><b><i>Om</i></b></p>
<p style="float: left;"><span class="m_5632504892163262824gmail-s1"><strong><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/web-_1_2048x2048.jpg?v=1556923544" style="margin-right: 20px; float: left;" width="226" height="263"></strong></span><strong>Nina Konjini</strong><br>Yoga found me eight years ago. My practice allows me to turn inward, to be a witness, to lean into the resistance and to surrender. On my mat, I found freedom and it is where peace finds me, over and over again. My intention is offer yoga to every body, to create community, and to hold space for healing. <br><br>I guide Yoga classes at Espace Rose Buddha in Montreal where these photographs were taken. </p>
<p style="float: left;"><br>You can find Nina on <strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/konjinius/">Instagram</a></strong> and on <strong><a href="https://www.facebook.com/nina.konjinius.1">Facebook</a></strong>. </p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="float: left;"><span> </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/conscious-parenting-with-taraneh-erfan-king</id>
    <published>2019-05-11T23:30:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-05-11T23:30:00-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/conscious-parenting-with-taraneh-erfan-king"/>
    <title>Conscious Parenting with Taraneh Erfan King</title>
    <author>
      <name>Claire Lester</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Motherhood (and parenthood in general) is not something that can be understood by the mind alone. No amount of reading about parenting in books, listening to experts speak or gaining anecdotal information from other parents, truly prepares us for the lived experience of the beautiful — albeit sometimes difficult — relationship with our children. </span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/conscious-parenting-with-taraneh-erfan-king">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Motherhood (and parenthood in general) is not something that can be understood by the mind alone. No amount of reading about parenting in books, listening to experts speak or gaining anecdotal information from other parents, truly prepares us for the lived experience of the beautiful — albeit sometimes difficult — relationship with our children. My near decade of experience as a counsellor, and my own journey as a mother, has taught me that even the most resourceful, patient and loving parents have challenging days.</span> </p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The experience of parenting can range from deep joy and elation to deep confusion and frustration. We sometimes hear that "it brings out the best in us” and “it brings out the worst in us.” Conscious parenting, as a concept, provides a shift in perspective on the function of parenting: it focuses on a higher state of awareness connected to our spiritual existence, which in turn creates a new paradigm for connection and healing with our children.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here are three steps you can take to more peacefully experience parenting, right now:</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<b>Listen to hear:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> A component of a heightened state of awareness is related to the way in which we listen. Listening to hear the other person in a conversation is energetically completely different than listening to respond to them or listening to relate to them. Listening to hear means we are listening fully without judgment, projection, or any element of our own ego interfering. It means we allow space for the full expression of the other person, and in our work to fully hear them, we create the conditions for them to be fully self-expressed. This even works for parenting babies through their body language.<br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<b>Presence:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> You can’t really hear someone if you are not present with them. As often as you can, find yourself in the NOW. Often we are operating from the past or the future, and our minds are busy perceiving things outside of the present moment. By tuning into our senses, and intentionally choosing the present moment over our thoughts about the past or future, we create the conditions to be fully available for our children. Without projections and fears meddling with the truth unfolding in front of us, we become capable of handling what arises with more grace, ease and resourcefulness.<br><br></span>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<b>Meditate:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> How do we embody presence and conscious listening? One of the best tools is the practice of meditation. If you aren’t already meditating, and you were waiting for a sign: this is it! I speak from experience when I say we become much more loving and kind parents when we meditate. Because meditation teaches us to remain detached from thought and habitual mental-gymnastics, as well as present and non-judgemental, it allows us to practice what it feels like inside our bodies to be at a restful responsive state. From this place we are able to tackle even the toughest situations from a place of clarity rather than reactivity. This increases both the state of inner peace we feel, and energetically, powerfully and positively impacts the state of peace between us and our children.</span> </li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mother’s Day is a great opportunity to celebrate our evolving state of consciousness through the experience of parenting. It can be a magical celebration of our awakening personally, as well as being conscious, loving guides for our children as they navigate their own paths. This Mother’s Day, perhaps consider the gift of awakening you are receiving through your experience as a mother, while also enjoying the gifts and expressions of love and gratitude you receive from others. You deserve both kinds of celebration!</span></p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/199-Taraneh-Erfan-King---Mind-on-Spirit_1200x1200_2048x2048.jpg?v=1551397137" style="margin-right: 20px; float: left;" width="254" height="254"><strong>Taraneh Erfan King</strong>, is a writer, educator and registered counsellor whose purpose is to hold space for conscious awakening. Her work is informed by her deep passion to create opportunities for inward development, and purpose-led transformation. She is currently focused on supporting parents in building conscious relationships with their children, allowing for the connection in their family unit to be a path to awakening, creating powerful ripples of healing and joy in all areas of their lives. Taraneh is also mom to two magic humans, and is writing a book on the topic of spiritual health and awakening. Learn more about Taraneh here: </span><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/www.mindonspirit.com">www.mindonspirit.com</a><span>. Photo by Scott Little Photography.</span></span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/6-tips-for-going-zero-waste-with-leah-payne</id>
    <published>2019-04-22T09:01:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-04-25T13:28:33-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/6-tips-for-going-zero-waste-with-leah-payne"/>
    <title>6 Tips for Going Zero Waste with Leah Payne</title>
    <author>
      <name>Claire Lester</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>I’ve always been a bit of a hippie at heart, but like many yogis, I knew I could step up my eco-friendly actions. So in 2019,  </span><strong><a href="https://leahstellapayne.com/2019/03/10/my-eco-friendly-resolution/">I made a resolution</a></strong><span> to drastically cut my waste (garbage and recycling) in favour of a more eco-friendly lifestyle.</span></p>
<p><span>In honour of Earth Day, here is some advice to those who may want to adopt their own Zero Waste habits.</span></p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/6-tips-for-going-zero-waste-with-leah-payne">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’ve always been a bit of a hippie at heart, but like many yogis, I knew I could step up my eco-friendly actions. So in 2019, </span><strong><a href="https://leahstellapayne.com/2019/03/10/my-eco-friendly-resolution/">I made a resolution</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to drastically cut my waste (garbage and recycling) in favour of a more eco-friendly lifestyle. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In honour of Earth Day, here is some advice to those who may want to adopt their own Zero Waste habits.</span></p>
<p><b>1. Be mindful<br></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Environmental activism and the principles of yoga go hand in hand. There’s a beautiful sense of interconnectedness that comes from practising mindfulness. Your yoga practice is a great opportunity to take a few moments to meditate and reflect daily on the fact that we are part of the environment—not separate from it. The more we do so, the more we can live this mindset off the mat.</span></p>
<p><b>2. Start small<br></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Think progress, not perfection. I’m not perfect, and I doubt that I’ll ever manage to be 100% Zero Waste. However, that shouldn’t stop us from trying! Every time you bring your own container for takeout, refill a container rather than buying a new bottle, or choose a biodegradable toothbrush instead of a plastic one, you’re making a difference. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I find it easier to take it slowly, and replace things as they wear out. Make one change at a time. When I ran out of snacks packaged in non-recyclable containers, I didn’t buy any more. When I ran out of regular plastic floss, I bought compostable silk floss. Next time I need a new lipstick, I’ll replace it with one in a more environmentally friendly container. </span></p>
<p><b>3. Make it your own<br></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">My zero-waste journey may look a bit different than your own, but that’s the beauty in it: you can adopt what makes sense for you and your lifestyle, and change what doesn’t. You may love DIY projects, or you may prefer to buy a premade product </span><strong><a href="https://www.thesoapdispensary.com/">at a refill store</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">. You may have a huge outdoor space for an expansive garden, or a tiny patio for a few containers.</span></p>
<p><b>4. Go au-natural  <br></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">We Zero Waste folk, choose to drastically reduce our use of plastic in favour of natural materials. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s easy to think that as long as plastic can be recycled it’s okay, but unfortunately that’s not the case. Unlike a glass jar, which can be recycled into another glass jar forever, plastic becomes weaker and of lower quality over time, so it’s only ever “downcycled.” When plastic gets into the environment, it’s extremely destructive and toxic, ending up in the oceans, in the bellies of sea creatures, and into our water supply. Even when we wash clothes made from synthetic materials, microscopic plastic pieces enter our waterways. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead, choose clothing made from natural materials, like cotton (organic is best!), hemp, linen, wool, or silk. When it comes to packaging or home goods, turn to what people used before plastics: glass, metal, wood, paper or cardboard, or natural cloth. There are some really lovely, inventive products out there, like non-toxic, natural, biodegradable food wraps made from beeswax-coated cloth.</span></p>
<p><b>5. Remember the other “R”s<br></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Recycling should be a last resort, after reducing and reusing. Also learn to “refuse” (promotional items, samples, or things you don’t want) and “repair” (rather than replacing).</span></p>
<p><b>6. Spread the word!<br></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">The real power comes from sharing what you’re doing with others. Tell your neighbours, your friends, your mom, your coworkers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I love bringing my own containers to restaurants, because I’ll often get comments and questions from other patrons. They’ve often just never thought of bringing their own, and I love thinking that I might have made a difference.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Also, reach out to politicians and companies to tell them your thoughts, and get involved in environmental organizations making a positive difference. Our actions, and our voices, can add up to something really beautiful!</span></p>
<p style="float: left;"><b><a href="https://leahstellapayne.com/"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/A40W3421_large.jpg?v=1555368296" style="margin-right: 20px; float: left;" width="188" height="282"></a>Leah Payne</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a Vancouver-based writer, editor, and blogger. When she’s not working or chasing her toddler son, she likes to collect children’s books, practise yoga, or try desperately to drink a cup of tea before it goes cold. Follow her zero-waste journey at her <strong><a href="https://leahstellapayne.com/">blog</a></strong></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and <strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/leahstellapayne/">Instagram</a></strong></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, or learn more about her writing and editing at</span><strong><a href="https://www.cedarhillcreative.ca/"> cedarhillcreative.ca</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="float: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span>Here at Halfmoon, we believe in taking steps towards a sustainable world however big or small. We make an effort within our sourcing, warehouse and production processes to take actions towards reducing our carbon footprint. </span></span></p>
<p><br><br></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/ocean-meditation-with-kirstin-clark</id>
    <published>2019-03-19T11:58:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-23T09:44:17-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/ocean-meditation-with-kirstin-clark"/>
    <title>Ocean Meditation with Kirstin Clark</title>
    <author>
      <name>Amanda Vitaro</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Slow down and picture yourself on a warm, peaceful beach breathing in the ocean air. Take 5 minutes out of your day to come into yourself and wind down with this guided ocean meditation by yoga teacher, Kirstin Clark. You'll be coming out feeling relaxed, rejuvenated and wishing you were really on a beach.  </span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/ocean-meditation-with-kirstin-clark">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>Slow down and picture yourself on a beach breathing in the ocean air. Pause and take 5 minutes out of your day to wind down with this guided meditation inspired by the rhythm of the ocean from yoga teacher Kirstin Clark. </p>
<p> </p>
<iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/581800011&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true"></iframe>  
<p> </p>
<p class="p1" style="float: left;"> </p>
<img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/53536627_980336768839298_1207616276738867200_n_1000x1200_medium.jpg?v=1552689290" style="margin-right: 20px; float: left;">
<p class="p1"><strong>Kirstin Clark</strong></p>
<p class="p1">Kristin is a certified yoga teacher from Vancouver B.C. She is also a certified personal trainer and is certified in RYT-200hr and 35hr Vinyasa Intensive. She teaches a range of different styles of yoga from vinyasa to restorative and meditation. She has a passion for helping others in obtaining a heathy lifestyle, and bringing balance on and off the mat. Currently, Kirstin teaches many classes around the lower mainland, as well as offering personal training, and private/small group classes. Find her on social media @coastal.yogi.</p>
<br>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br> </span></p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/the-science-of-sleep</id>
    <published>2019-03-14T09:38:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2020-10-16T09:46:36-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/the-science-of-sleep"/>
    <title>The Science of Sleep</title>
    <author>
      <name>Candace Fan</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>We spend up to one-third of our lives asleep but many of us are not actually “great in bed”. You probably already know that getting a good night’s sleep is essential to your overall health and well-being and that most people require a solid eight hours per night to maintain good sleep health. </span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/the-science-of-sleep">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If there is one thing most of us are short on in today’s society, its sleep, says Stephanie Kersta MSc, RP and Carolyn Plater MSW, RSW, Registered Psychotherapists, Sleep Specialists and co-founders of</span><a href="http://www.hoame.ca/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Hoame</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. When people ask you, “How’s it going?” or “How are you?”, you may frequently find yourself responding with, “I’m tired,” and it’s very likely that you are. According to a study by Aviva (2016) in the UK, Canada is the third most sleep-deprived country with 31% of Canadians feeling like they don’t get enough sleep. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We spend up to one-third of our lives asleep but many of us are not actually “great in bed”. You probably already know that getting a good night’s sleep is essential to your overall health and well-being and that most people require a solid eight hours per night to maintain good sleep health. Sleep promotes healthy brain function, emotional well-being, decreases risk of obesity and chronic diseases, and improves daytime performance and safety (National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, 2017). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, many of us are actually experiencing what experts call “sleep debt” (National Sleep Foundation, n.d.). Similar to paying off a mortgage or credit card, if we let those payments slip, interest accumulates making paying off the balance that much more difficult down the road. The more sleep you lose, the more difficult it becomes to catch up on that much needed shut eye. </span></p>
<p><b>The Science of Sleep</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Accumulating sleep debt can feel very stressful. On the flip side, stress is also a contributor to losing sleep. If you’ve ever been under considerable stress, you may have found it difficult to fall asleep and to stay asleep, which consequently affects the overall quality of your time in bed. So what’s the connection? Why are sleep and stress so interconnected? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stress changes the activity of the hormones in your body (e.g., cortisol, epinephrine, adrenaline, etc.). Sleep is an important component of maintaining balance in these hormones and the systems of your body. However, chronic stress causes your body to enter “flight-or-fight” as a defence mechanism to try and get your body back to a more balanced state. Over time, these defences may weaken or fail which can lead to insomnia or issues with sleeping (Sun Han, Kim, &amp; Shim, 2012). The system in your body responsible for the beginning and end of sleep, the hypothalamo-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) axis, is impacted when stress is present (Sun Han, Kim, &amp; Shim, 2012). This may explain why falling asleep and staying asleep is so difficult when you’re feeling stressed. </span></p>
<p><b>Tips to Make You Great in Bed</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sleep is critical to ensuring balance in your physical, mental, emotional, and spiritual health. To find the balance, we’ve compiled some tips you may consider in order to improve your “sleep hygiene”: </span></p>
<p><strong><i>Create a Personalized Sleep Schedule and Stick to It!</i></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> One of the best ways to start improving sleep hygiene is to create a sleep schedule. To try and get those eight hours of sleep per night, choose your bedtime and waking time and set alarms for both. On the weekends, you may feel like turning off those alarms but try not to. Keeping a consistent sleep schedule means that those long sleep-ins or naps on the weekend may no longer feel necessary. Over time, your body will get used to its new schedule which means waking up may even be possible without the alarm!</span></p>
<p><strong><i>Introduce Bedtime Rituals.</i></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Incorporating ways to wind down after a long day is something that is often missing from the daily routine. However, it’s important to take on a slower pace and get yourself ready for sleep. Kersta recommends taking a hot bath, meditating, doing some light yoga poses, or reading a few pages of a book (not on an electronic device).  Plater suggests applying some soothing essential oils to the bottoms of your feet, to set the tone for your night ahead. Plater and Kersta both recommend lavender, chamomile or neroli which have sedating properties.</span></p>
<p><strong><i>Exercise Regularly.</i></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Engaging in physical activity every day, several hours before bedtime can actually help you fall asleep faster and promote a deeper sleep. However, don’t run 5km right before bedtime – exercise stimulates the secretion of cortisol which activates the alerting mechanism in the brain (Division of Sleep Medicine at Harvard Medical School, n.d.). Try to exercise early in the day up to 3 hours before you fall asleep. </span></p>
<p><b><i>Limit Your Sleep Stealers.</i></b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Alcohol and caffeine before bed can impact a good night’s rest. This is because they are both stimulants – caffeine can keep you awake while alcohol can increase the number of times you wake up in the night. Limit caffeine at least six hours before bed and avoid consuming alcohol within three hours of bedtime (Division of Sleep Medicine at Harvard Medical School, n.d.).</span></p>
<p><b><i>Create a Sleep-Inducing Environment.</i></b> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Changing your bedroom is another way you promote good sleep hygiene. The first step is to limit your bedroom activities to sleep and sex only. Think about removing your computer, TV, work materials, and your phone out of the bedroom so that you can begin associating your bedroom with sleep only. You may also want to limit other distractions: </span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">       </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you have a pet that wakes you up throughout the night, keep them out of your bedroom. </span>
</li>
<li>
<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">       </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">If there are distracting noises outside, consider earplugs, a white noise machine, or a fan. </span>
</li>
<li>
<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">       </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keep your room cool and dark with air conditioning, black out shades, or wear an eye mask. </span>
</li>
<li>
<span style="font-weight: 400;"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">       </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Change your bedding or pillows to make your bed as comfortable as possible. </span>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.hoame.ca/">Hoame</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a World Sleep Day 2019 Delegate, and on March 15, has a full day of sleep-themed programming and services. Don’t miss it!</span></p>
<p> </p>
<img alt="Carolyn Plater &amp; Stephanie Kersta" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/Hoame-Care-and-Steph-Bio-photo_240x240_medium.jpg?v=1551809631" style="float: left; margin-right: 20px;">
<p style="float: left;"><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Carolyn Plater</strong><br> <br>Carolyn Plater graduated with an Honours BA. in Psychology from York University. She received her Addiction Education Diploma from McMaster University and her Masters of Social Work degree from the University of Toronto, which included a joint collaborative program in Addiction Studies. As a compliment to her strong clinical education Carolyn has incorporated additional evidence based holistic certificates to further round out her training. Carolyn is a certified trauma-informed yoga instructor, and provides yoga training and yoga therapy in both private and group sessions. She holds a certificate from University of Toronto in Applied Mindfulness Meditation and also has a certificate in Plant-Based Nutrition from Cornell University.</p>
<p class="p1"><b>Stephanie Kersta</b></p>
<p class="p1">Stephanie Kersta holds an Honors Bachelor of Science with a specialty in Psychology, and a Masters of Science in Psychology. As a compliment to her strong clinical education, Stephanie has incorporated additional evidence-based holistic certificates to further round out her training. She is a certified in Applied Mindfulness Meditation, Mindfulness Based Stress Reduction, Mindfulness Based Cognitive Therapy, Mindful Eating, and holds a certificate in Plant-Based Nutrition from Cornell University. Stephanie holds teaching positions at both McMaster University and Durham College in their Addiction and Mental Health programs and is a consultant trainer for the Canadian Training Institute.</p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/how-to-choose-your-sit-set</id>
    <published>2019-03-08T13:28:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2019-03-11T11:25:09-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/how-to-choose-your-sit-set"/>
    <title>How to Choose a Meditation Sit Set</title>
    <author>
      <name>Candace Fan</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8"><span>Need help choosing the perfect setup for your meditation practice? Consider a Sit Set! This product combines a supportive cushion with a zabuton that insulates and cradles your feet and ankles for extra comfort. Now, lets break down the differences between each set we offer and help you choose the best option for your body!</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/how-to-choose-your-sit-set">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Need help getting comfortable in your meditation practice? Consider a meditation sit set! This product combines a supportive buckwheat filled meditation cushion—which comes in a variety of shapes—paired with a zabuton that insulates and cradles your feet and ankles for extra comfort. Now, lets break down the differences between each set we offer and help you choose the best option for your body! </p>
<p><b><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/round-meditation-cushion-zabuton" target="_blank" title="Round Meditation + Zabuton Sit Set" rel="noopener noreferrer">Round Meditation Cushion + Zabuton</a></b> </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/products/halfmoon-meditation-cushion-zabuton-1?variant=21480002256956" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img alt="Round Sit Set" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/Round-Meditation-Cushion-Zabuton-Light-Denim-Linen-frontal__1200x600_1024x1024.jpg?v=1552328291" style="float: none;"></a>The Round Sit Set combines a classic meditation cushion shape with traditional pleated sides and a matching zabuton. At 5" tall, this set is a great option if you have moderately open to very open hips. This is a great set for beginners and seasoned practitioners alike.</span></p>
<br>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/mod-meditation-cushion-zabuton" target="_blank" title="Mod Meditation Cushion + Zabuton" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Mod Meditation Cushion + Zabuton</b></a></p>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/mod-meditation-cushion-zabuton" title="Mod Meditation Cushion + Zabuton"><b><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0040/3098/8386/files/mod_1200x600_1024x1024.jpg?v=1550274676" alt=""></b></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Mod Sit Set is designed with more height to allow those with tighter hips to relax and soften while meditating at 5.5" in height. The modern lines of this set look great with any home decor. Use this set as a sitting cushion for your guests or as part of a dedicated meditation zone. </span></p>
<br>
<p><b><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/halfmoon-zafu-zabuton" target="_blank" title="Halfmoon Meditation Cushion + Zabuton" rel="noopener noreferrer">Halfmoon Meditation Cushion + Zabuton</a></b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/products/halfmoon-meditation-cushion-zabuton-1?variant=21480004386876" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/FrontHalfmoon_ZabLimitedEdition_Natural_1200x600_1024x1024.jpg?v=1552328356" alt=""></a>The Halfmoon Sit Set is designed to provide a wider and a more stable base for support during your meditation practice. With the same 5" height as the Round Sit Set, the Halfmoon Sit Set is great for people who like to sit with their ankles tucked in close to their body and have moderate to very open hips. </span></p>
<br>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/home-meditation-cushion-zabuton-1" target="_blank" title="Home Meditation Cushion + Zabuton" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b>Home Meditation Cushion + Zabuton</b></a></p>
<p><a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/home-meditation-cushion-zabuton-1" target="_blank" title="Home Meditation Cushion + Zabuton" rel="noopener noreferrer"><b><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0040/3098/8386/files/homesitset_1200x1000_1024x1024.jpg?v=1550274669" alt=""></b></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Home Sit Set features the widest cushion and offers the most steady and supported base of all. Compared to the Round Sit Set, the Home Sit Set is 6” tall and can support tighter hips by softening and relaxing them during your meditation. With a similar look as the Mod Sit Set, this cushion also looks fantastic with any home decor!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to learn more about all the meditation cushions we offer? Check out this handy <strong><a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/Halfmoon_cushion_compare_r8_2018JulyPRINTS_SMALL.pdf?15758019174061211310">comparison chart</a> </strong>or browse all of our <a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/meditation-cushions" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">meditation cushions</a>!</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/women-pushing-their-limits</id>
    <published>2019-03-07T11:22:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2019-03-09T09:38:31-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/women-pushing-their-limits"/>
    <title>Women Pushing Their Limits</title>
    <author>
      <name>Candace Fan</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8"><span>Happy International Women's Day! Everyday, we are surrounded by such powerful, strong and inspiring women that radiates light into this world - it simply cannot be ignored. Here is a conversation with four ladies that not only live a passionate yogic lifestyle, but push their limits everyday in pursuing their dreams.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/women-pushing-their-limits">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p class="p1"><em>Photo by Bryanna Bradley Photography. <a href="http://www.bryannabradley.ca/"><span class="s1">http://www.bryannabradley.ca/</span></a></em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;">Happy International Women's Day! Everyday, we are surrounded by such powerful, strong and inspiring women that radiate light into this world — it simply cannot be ignored. Here is a conversation with four ladies that not only live a passionate yogic lifestyle, but push their limits everyday in pursuing their dreams.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"> </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><img alt="Katherine Moore" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/IMG_1523_medium.JPG?v=1551397143" style="float: left; margin-right: 20px;"></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><b>Katherine Moore</b></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Katherine has been teaching yoga for 18 years and competing in distance running for 13 years.  Her love for health, movement, stillness, breath, and alignment shines through when she is teaching.  Katherine is passionate about the benefits of yoga for everyone. She loves organizing retreats and workshops, both locally and internationally to encourage everyone to dive deeper into their practice.  She is inspired to share her passions with everyone and see how they can be a positive light to everyone’s life, and always with the brightest smile on her face. Find her at </span><a href="http://runningintoyoga.ca/" style="color: #666666;" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Runningintoyoga.ca</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> or @runningintoyoga.</span></span></p>
<p> </p>
<p style="float: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #666666;"><strong><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/IMG_4491_1024x1024_medium.jpg?v=1551980213" style="float: left; margin-right: 20px;"></strong></span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #666666;"><strong>Dora Kamau</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #666666;">Dora Kamau is a mental health </span><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #666666;">visionary, self-care advocate and the founder of Bliss Your Heart, an online and in-person women’s platform rooted in self-care, self-love and mental health. After a near death experience at birth and overcoming a serious of unfortunate events in her teenage years, Dora transmuted her shortcomings as a catalyst for growth into the multifaceted woman she is today. She has made it her life’s purpose and soul mission to guide other women on their journey to wholeness &amp; wellness. Whether it’s through her online presence or in-person events and workshops, she creates and holds space for women to step into their power &amp; offers a new perspective on life. Aside from being a student of life, Dora also holds a BA in Psychology, with a specialization in adolescent psychology and is in her final year of completing her BSc. in Psychiatric Nursing. Find her @dora_kamau or @blissyourheart.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"> </span></p>
<img alt="Taraneh Efran King" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/199-Taraneh-Erfan-King---Mind-on-Spirit_1200x1200_medium.jpg?v=1551397137" style="float: left; margin-right: 20px;">
<p style="float: left;"><span style="color: #666666;"><b>Taraneh</b></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"> <strong>Erfan King</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #666666;">Taraneh Erfan King, is a writer, educator and registered counsellor whose purpose is to hold space for conscious awakening. Her work is informed by her deep passion to create opportunities for inward development, and purpose-led transformation. She is currently focused on supporting parents in building conscious relationships with their children, allowing for the connection in their family unit to be a path to awakening, creating powerful ripples of healing and joy in all areas of their lives. Taraneh is also mom to two magic humans, and is writing a book on the topic of spiritual health and awakening. Learn more about Taraneh here: <a href="www.mindonspirit.com">www.mindonspirit.com</a>. Photo by Scott Little Photography.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"> </span></p>
<p style="float: left;"><span style="color: #666666;"> </span></p>
<p style="float: left;"><span style="color: #666666;"> </span></p>
<p style="float: left;"><span style="color: #666666;"><strong><img alt="Melody Walford" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/DSC_1354_1024x1024_medium.jpg?v=1551893077" style="margin-right: 20px; float: left;"></strong></span></p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><strong>Melody Walford<br></strong></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;">Melody was raised on a small farm on Hornby Island, off the coast of Vancouver Island where her exploration of alternative living began. Her yoga training includes both Vinyasa and Yoga Therapy. She has an Integrative Massage and Yoga Therapy practice in Tofino, B.C, where she currently resides. She also holds a Diploma of Acupuncture from Pacific Rim College and awaiting her final exam results to become a Registered Acupuncturist (R. Ac). She wholeheartedly believes in the power of holistic medicine. She encourages people to use their hearts, bodies, breath, creativity and vulnerability in order to transform. Her approach in both yoga teaching and massage is to guide others using non-intrusive, gentle, and intuitive methods. Find Melody @melodynicolewalford. Images by Bryanna Bradley photography.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<span style="color: #666666;"><strong>1. How does the practice of yoga inform your other projects/passions? What aspects of yoga have you incorporated into your process?</strong><br><br><b>Katherine</b></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">The practice of yoga helps me be more patient with myself. When I’m organizing and planning my retreats and my training, things do not always go the way I plan. Yoga helps me to slow down, take a step back, breathe and reassess where things may have gone wrong or if I need to take a break. I meditate and I ask questions as it really works for me. Within a few days, the answers will usually show up. When I get into the flow, running becomes my meditation and my yoga. It’s that present moment experience where it is just me and the trail. It’s beautiful how yoga and running are very similar that way.<br><br><strong>Dora</strong><br>Being in the flow and being slow and intentional are two aspects of yoga that I’ve incorporated in my life. I wouldn’t say I practice yoga to the point where it has informed my projects and passions, but the teachings within the practice are what I use and implement daily. Returning back to my breath and being mindful while my breath feeds my mind and my emotions, have been the most useful tools in my journey thus far.<br><br><strong>Taraneh</strong><br>Yoga allows me to come home to my Self again and again. Every time I step onto my mat, I move through more than just an asana practice. I allow the teachings of yoga (such as the yamas and the niyamas) to inform my practice in body, mind and spirit. This practice leaves me nourished, calm and at peace with the present moment, which is all there ever is. It is this presence that supports all aspects of my life, including projects and passions.<br><br><strong>Melody</strong><br>Yoga stabilises me in what is true and real. It clears the way for energy to flow and reminds me of life’s beauty and ease. It simply helps me not freak out about the small stuff and gain some grounded perspective. It is my best friend in regulating my nervous system, so I can attend to the details of life without getting consumed by them. Every once and a while I feel my expansiveness and Divinity--this is so important so I don’t get lost in my thoughts and fears. </span>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><br></span><strong style="color: #666666;">2. Aside from yoga, what else ignites your soul? </strong><br><span style="color: #666666;"><strong></strong></span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8"><br><span style="color: #666666;"><b>Katherine</b></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">Waking up everyday I take a moment to be thankful for what I have - my health, family, friends, my dog- Sheba, and the work that I do. It ignites my soul to get up and be my best self, love myself and live a healthy lifestyle, in which I feel that I can inspire others to do the same.</span><br> <meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><strong>Dora</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">My deep appreciation for life and my curiosity of its intricacy is what ignites my soul. Also, a cold ataulfo mango on a hot summer day is equally igniting.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><strong>Taraneh</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">I come alive when I am engaged in the topic of consciousness, whether it be through my one-on-one work with clients, teaching, writing, reading, or in dialogue with others. I find a deep sense of joy and excitement, as well as curiosity and openness when considering the bigger questions in life, like “Who am I?” and “How can I best contribute?”</span></p>
<span style="color: #666666;"> <strong>Melody</strong></span><br>
<p><span style="color: #666666;">I am drawn to the wild with all of my being. Surfing is a passion that has been with me for over 13 years now and continues to wake me up to present. I have learned that I need a lot of laughter and play in my life to help me balance my intensity and tendency to strive. This helps me to soften and let go of the stress that accumulates in my body. I love to sing (badly) but I do it anyway. Deep nourishment for my soul comes from my friends and boyfriend who inspire me and help me relax. I love to travel and wandering without a goal--this is really healing for me. Culture awakens me to the incredible diversity and capacity this earth has. Looking at the stars at night reminds me of my smallness and yet significance in this big Universe-I need this regularly. Finally, dancing helps me to move stuck energy and trapped emotions in a way that feels very therapeutic and soul awakening!</span><br><strong style="color: #444444;"></strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong style="color: #444444;">3. What drives you to push the limits in your field? What keeps you motivated?</strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><strong>Katherine</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">I love to push the limits in my field by always learning. I make an effort to take a class that is taught by someone with more experience at least once a week. It recharges my batteries. I am at my best when I practice consistently, and I find it very important to keep a regular routine. I stay motivated in running as I want to see what I can achieve. With hard work and dedication, I surprised myself many times by seeing how the impossible became possible.</span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><strong>Dora</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">Other than being a devout Capricorn, what motivates me is the potential impact that lies within me to change the world or be a part of that change. What drives me to push the limits in my field is the existing limitations that have been set by outdated paradigms, programs and beliefs.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><strong>Taraneh</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">I am committed to being an active participant in creating a healthier, happier, more connected global community, and a better tomorrow for all beings. I know that in order to create positive change and healing in our world, we must begin healing from within and understand that we have a powerful ripple effect. Ultimately, it is my deep love for the world that motivates me in my work: to invite others along on the journey of Self-awareness, and taking responsibility for shifting our individual and then our collective experience towards more peace and harmony.</span><br><span style="color: #666666;"><strong></strong></span></p>
<span style="color: #666666;"> <strong>Melody</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">My student’s gratitude is a big force in keeping my in line with my aim. I keep coming back to the look in a person’s eyes when something lands within them. I remember having those moments and they have shaped me. I also remind myself that life is precious and we have limited time here in this body, it is not to be wasted in worry and fear. Honestly, following love just feels so much better!<strong> </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span> </span>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"> </span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><strong style="color: #444444;">4. What advice do you have for women to establish a new passion or find their calling?</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><strong>Katherine</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">My advice is to follow your dreams. Don’t wait. After my first yoga class, I knew that I was going to teach yoga one day. When I completed my yoga teacher training, I was so scared. I wanted to wait till I was “ready”, but the studio owner had put me on the schedule at 6am the next day. I was terrified, I did not want to do it. I don’t remember much about the first class except how much I was shaking and how scared I was, but my sister was there to support me. After that, I made myself go back and keep teaching. Stalk your fears, and do what scares you! If you are comfortable, you are not in the right place- learn to get comfortable with being uncomfortable, that’s where you grow.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><strong>Dora</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">Your authenticity can never be replicated. Something that I had to overcome was the feeling of being an imposter. I’m sure that is a feeling that a lot of people experience when they are pursuing their passion. You might feel inadequate, unworthy, lacking experience or feel like you have nothing to offer because it’s already been done but, YOU can never be replicated. You can be imitated, however it will never be as good as the blueprint. Every other individual on this earth has something unique to offer. Our gifts are shaped by our past, our experiences and our perspectives. Those aspects are reflected in the work we bring forth. When you’re establishing a new passion or finding your calling, it is possible that it has already been done, but someone, somewhere is in search of what you have to offer.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><strong>Taraneh</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">Gift yourself with time and space to sit in silence, cultivating presence each day. Out of our stillness and quiet, a deep inner wisdom arises to support us in finding the way to (and through) our passions, callings, and life experience in general.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"><strong>Melody</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">Follow ease and give yourself permission to let go of inner judgement. We all could slow down and find kindness and genuine care for ourselves in this intense world. I would say take time to be quiet and listen, allowing the senses to guide so you can tune into the whispers beneath the surface of distraction, conditioning, and outside influence. It is here you can get really clear on what is true for you. We all know what lights us up but we get confused. Meet yourself with the most loving softness and see what changes.</span></p>
<p><br><span style="color: #666666;"><strong>5. How would you like to make an impact in this world? What do you want to be remembered for? </strong></span><br><br><span style="color: #666666;" mce-data-marked="1"><strong>Katherine</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">I want to make an impact by being a part of a community of like-minded people and sharing my passions and encouraging others to do the same. Yoga brings awareness, mindfulness, love and kindness to ourselves and to others which creates a peaceful world. I created ‘Runningintoyoga’ retreats to bring together like-minded people and encourage a healthy lifestyle through meditation, movement and nutrition. I want to be remembered as a positive influence, someone that lived life to their fullest, and showed the world that anything is possible with a great sense of humour.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;"> <strong>Dora</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">My greatest impact would just be to be remembered for who I was. Authentically, truly and in alignment with my purpose. I hope that when people remember me, they remember me for who I was and I think that will be impactful on it’s own.</span><br><br><span style="color: #666666;"><strong>Taraneh</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">If there is one thing I hope people experience in my presence in this lifetime, it is kindness. </span><br><br><span style="color: #666666;"><strong>Melody</strong></span><br><span style="color: #666666;">The energy that I radiate. For me it really is the simple things, like a moment of true connection, like a genuine smile from deep inside. I would love to hear that my presence was calmly uplifting and that sharing space helped others to see and feel a depth of their own brilliance and beauty. If by my presence on this earth there was a little more love and acceptance I would be really stoked! <br></span><strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #666666;">We hope you have a wonderful day of celebrating the amazing women in your lives. Keep standing in your power and continue living your passionate lives.  </span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/forest-bath</id>
    <published>2019-02-19T13:55:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-19T13:55:36-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/forest-bath"/>
    <title>Forest Bathing by Mara Branscombe</title>
    <author>
      <name>Candace Fan</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Originating in Japan in the 1980’s “Shinrin Yoku” otherwise known as forest bathing literally translates as “taking in the forest atmosphere.” The scientific research done on forest bathing is quite amazing — tree’s (especially coniferous ones) release an organic compound called “phytoncide”.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/forest-bath">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Originating in Japan in the 1980’s “Shinrin Yoku” otherwise known as forest bathing literally translates as “taking in the forest atmosphere.” The scientific research done on forest bathing is quite amazing — tree’s (especially coniferous ones) release an organic compound called “phytoncide”. This compound</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">supports our natural killer cells that allow our immune system to fight diseases such as cancer, ward off illnesses and keep our immune system strong.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The concept is quite simple: spend meditative time in nature by walking, sitting, or lying down for at least 1-4 hours. By slowing down, and allowing the forest’s atmosphere to penetrate your whole being, the nervous system will calm and trigger a relaxation and healing response within. This is very different than a trail run, a hike, or any physical activity that gets the heart rate up. Forest Bathing is a deep release of any agenda or exercise, and requires a letting go of external energy output to receive the benefits of Mother Earth’s finest energy.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Intuitively many cultures from past to present have practiced this receptive form of connection to the forest and the elements, yet as technology and stress related imbalances/illnesses are on the rise, Forest Bathing is a potent reminder of how to enhance a peaceful and healing connection towards ourselves, each other, and Mother Earth.</span></p>
<br>
<p><strong>How to forest bathe:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Find a peaceful place in the forest or nature where you can truly relax.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leave your phone at home or turn it off</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Set a personal intention to slow down, to fully connect to the natural environment, to let go of any agenda and commit to the experience of whatever arises in the present moment</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Walk slowly, find a tree to sit against, or lie down on the earth</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consciously allow your breath to slow down and take an easeful rhythm</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Listen to the soundscape, witness the shapes and the colours around you, and stay connected to nature’s scents</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Open your senses to receive the healing and medicinal energy that lives in the forest ecosystem. Imagine the positive energy living in the forest to penetrate your being</span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.natureandforesttherapy.org/about/science">Benefits of forest bathing:</a></strong></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Decreases the stress hormone, cortisol</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Boosts immune system</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Increases energy levels and enhances positive mood</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Improves sleep</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reduces blood pressure</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Supports recovery from illness</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Increases ability to focus</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Supports connection to intuition, positive self esteem, and connection to nature</span></li>
</ul>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forest Bathing and spending time in nature inspires us to re-connect to the earth, to our natural ecosystem, to our communities and to ourselves. Forest Bathing is an intentional practice where the attention placed on the present moment and connection to nature becomes your intuitive guide.  Similar to meditation, and other mindful practices, it takes time to cultivate the presence of patience, relaxation, and release. I encourage you to take up the art of forest bathing, to rest in the arms of mother earth’s finest energy, and to make rebalancing your own energy a priority. May we inspire each other through our own grounded, graceful and focused nature.</span></p>
<p>Here is a poem by nature poet Mary Oliver to inspire us to practice the art of forest bathing and in finding reverence for the trees:</p>
<br>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Around me the tree’s stir</span></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In their leaves and </span></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Call out, </span></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stay a while.</span></div>
<br>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">By Mary Oliver</span></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<div class="article_content clearfix">
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<p style="float: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong><a href="http://www.marabranscombe.com/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.marabranscombe.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1544229816063000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHUXOm4zD-HFCiTRyjPv7pVCDuCCg" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/MaraBio-large_medium.jpg?v=1544143648" style="float: left; margin-right: 20px;"></a>Mara Branscombe</strong><br><span>In her yoga teachings, Mara weaves together her background as a dance artist, her practice in the shamanic tradition, and her twenty years of experience on her mat – naturally what arises is a fluid, earthy, full bodied practice. Currently, Mara hosts international yoga retreats, </span></span><span>offers online courses, fuses yoga and corporate leadership to executive teams, teaches professional athletes and artists, mentors yoga teachers and teaches classes/workshops. Mara is a mother of two in Vancouver, BC. Find out more about Mara on her website at </span><a href="http://www.marabranscombe.com/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.marabranscombe.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1544229816063000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHUXOm4zD-HFCiTRyjPv7pVCDuCCg" rel="noopener noreferrer">www.marabranscombe.com</a><span>. <strong></strong></span></p>
<p style="float: left;"> </p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="float: left;"><span>Join Mara at Hollyhock June 14-19, 2019 for a Summer Solstice Retreat where forest bathing will be on the agenda at <a href="https://marabranscombe.com/events/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://marabranscombe.com/events/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1550341168062000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFG4muTGrxACHlaISoOIRAlNo-nzQ" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://marabranscombe.com/<wbr></wbr>events/</a></span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<div></div>
</div>
<div class="author_share_wrap">
<div class="blog_share meta">
<div class="share_article">
<div class="social_buttons">
<div class="share-btn twitter"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/self-love-sequence</id>
    <published>2019-02-12T14:11:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T14:17:03-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/self-love-sequence"/>
    <title>Yoga for Self-Love</title>
    <author>
      <name>Candace Fan</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><meta charset="utf-8"><span>This self-love yoga sequence is full of juicy heart openers. Fill your own cup this holiday season and bring your best self to the world.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/self-love-sequence">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>This self-love yoga sequence is full of juicy heart openers. Fill your own cup this holiday season and bring your best self to the world.</p>
<p><b>1. Seated Pose</b></p>
<p>Start by sitting tall on a meditation cushion or block. Bring your left hand to your heart and your right hand to your belly. Noticing your natural breath. Feel it flow through your heart and into your belly. This is the prefect time to set an intention of self-love and gratitude for your practice that is just for you.</p>
<br>
<p><b>2. Restorative Twist</b></p>
<p> </p>
<p>For this restorative twist, place your rectangular bolster along the middle of your mat. Bring your right hip to the bottom of the bolster with your legs bent, left leg on top of the right leg. With your eyes closed, mindfully lower your upper body down to the bolster with an arm on either side. You may also place a block in between your legs to release any tension in your back. Stay here for 2-3 minutes on each side. This twist allows your nervous system to relax.</p>
<br>
<p><b>3. Supported Heart Opener</b></p>
<p><span>This heart-opening pose is a great way to invite love into your practice.Sitting at the bottom of your rectangular bolster, slowly lay down. Bend both legs and bring the soles of your feet together, let your knees fall to either side. Feel free to support your knees with blocks if your hips are feeling tight. Allow your arms to fall to the ground on either side of you, feeling your heart open with every inhale and exhale.</span></p>
<br>
<p><b>4. Pigeon Pose</b></p>
<p><span>Start on your hands and knees to come into your pigeon pose. Bring your right knee to your right wrist, and place your shin on a diagonal angle then extend your back leg out. Take hold of your strap with your hands slightly wider than shoulder width apart. Bring your arms over your head stretching out your shoulders. You can invite another heart opener here, bending your back slightly while opening up your hips.</span></p>
<br>
<p><b>5. Camel Pose</b></p>
<p><span>Come down to your knees and sit back on your heels. Your knees should be hip distance apart. Start to engage your glutes and press your hips up off your heels and onto your knees. Place your hands on your lower back, fingers pointing down towards the ground. While your hands slowly make their way down towards your heels, arch your back and open up your chest towards the ceiling. Feel free to keep your chin tucked or let your head fall back if you feel comfortable.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><b>6. Legs Up The Wall</b></p>
<p><span>This pose is the best way to give your legs and feet a break and return that old blood back to your heart. Start by lying down on your back with your sit bones against the wall and shift your feet up the wall (or couch). Let your heels press up towards the ceiling and feel the gravity weighing on your hips. You may also place a block or a blanket under your hips for a higher elevation.</span></p>
<br>
<p><b>7. Restorative Bridge Pose with Bolster</b></p>
<p><span>For this inversion, you will need a bolster. Start by lying flat on your mat with your knees bent and the heels of your feet close to your sit bones. Engage your glutes and your core to push your hips up and slide the bolster underneath your sacrum. Breathe deeply into your pose as your lungs open and the tension of your lower back releases</span></p>
<br>
<p><b>8. Savasana</b></p>
<p><b></b><span>Savasana is the best self-nurturing pose for the end of your practice. You can place a bolster underneath your knees for extra support and let your body sink into your mat. Use this time to come back into your breath and your intention of your self-love you set at the beginning of practice.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/6-ways-to-use-a-cotton-yoga-blanket</id>
    <published>2019-01-30T15:21:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-10-05T11:31:52-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/6-ways-to-use-a-cotton-yoga-blanket"/>
    <title>6 Ways to Use a Cotton Yoga Blanket</title>
    <author>
      <name>Claire Lester</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Need a yoga practice on the go, but didn’t bring your full prop collection? No worries - we’ve got you covered with a series of restorative postures that need only a blanket for support. Follow along with this sequence, holding each posture anywhere between 3-10 minutes.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/6-ways-to-use-a-cotton-yoga-blanket">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Need a yoga practice on the go, but didn’t bring your full prop collection? No worries - we’ve got you covered with a series of restorative postures that need only a <a href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/collections/blankets" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>blanket</strong></a> for support. Follow along with this sequence, holding each posture anywhere between 3-10 minutes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>1. Legs-up-the-wall</strong><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ultimate restorative posture. If you’re tired from a day of being on your feet, this is for you. Fold your blanket lengthwise, and place it against a wall, on top of your mat. Lie down on your back, and shuffle your hips up close to the wall, resting on the blanket for support. Swing your legs up to the wall and let your heels press against the support. Your knees may bend slightly. Feel the heaviness drop out of your feet, and breathe deeply.</span> </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>2. Restorative hip opener</strong><br><br>This gentle hip opener will help ease tension in your hip flexers and lower back. To support your knee joint on the floor, fold up a blanket to any thickness, and slide your knee onto the support of your cotton yoga blanket. Palms can stack under your forehead, or you can gaze to one side. Stay for an equal time on both sides of the body.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>3. Child’s pose</strong><br><br></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For a pose that is supposed to be restful, Child’s pose or Balasana, can cause a lot of tension to the knees. Folding the blanket to bridge the gap between your hips and heels will let you settle deeper and more comfortably into the pose.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>4. Spinal Twist</strong><br><br>Take some pressure off your hips and make your twist a little gentler by placing a folded blanket between your knees. Turn your gaze away from your legs and relax into this pose. After a few minutes bring your knees back to centre, then switch sides.</span></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span><strong>5. Savasana</strong><br><br></span><span>For lower-back support in your savasana, roll up your blanket and place it under your knees. Bring your feet a little wider than the hips and let your toes fall out to each side. Take your time to adjust your position, and rest for as long as you need.</span></p>
<p><span><strong>6. Savasana II</strong><br><br></span><span>When your body is deep in relaxation, you can definitely get chilly. The support and gentle weight of your cotton yoga blanket will provide some warmth and comfort at the end of any class.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="float: left;"><span><strong><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/image1_6_large.jpeg?v=1548890035" style="margin-right: 20px; float: left;" width="263" height="263">Liv Law</strong> is a yoga and pilates teacher in Vancouver offering powerful, all-level classes. Follow her on Instagram <a href="https://www.instagram.com/yogi_liv/?hl=en">@yogi_liv</a> and her website <a href="http://livlawyoga.com/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://livlawyoga.com&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1538001785663000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE9lecyttVy9nEGahAP-mqrTv1ngw" rel="noopener noreferrer">livlawyoga.com</a>!</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/new-year-new-intentions</id>
    <published>2019-01-04T08:48:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-24T11:39:38-08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/new-year-new-intentions"/>
    <title>New Year, New Intentions</title>
    <author>
      <name>Claire Lester</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span>Many people take this opportunity to resolve to eat healthier, save money or achieve the next career milestone. But too often, stress and exhaustion take over as the weeks go by. So in order to thrive, put aside the goal setting for a moment and focus on you. Reflect on how you want to show up for 2021 — your attitude, your attention, your integrity. How can you rise above the burnout epidemic and show up to life with your full self? </span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://shophalfmoon.ca/blogs/balance-blog/new-year-new-intentions">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The beginning of the year offers us the a chance to leave elements of our old selves in the past and recreate our new selves with hope and confidence. Many people take this opportunity to resolve to eat healthier, save money or achieve their next career milestone. But, too often, stress and exhaustion take over as the weeks go by leading to frustration and disappointment.<br><br>In order to thrive, put aside goal setting and take a moment to focus on you. Reflect on how you want to show up for 2021 — your attitude, your attention, your integrity. How can you rise above the burnout epidemic and show up to life with your full self?</p>
<p>Here are four suggestions for creating a joyful, burnout-free 2021.</p>
<p><strong> 1. Say no to say yes to you<br></strong>Every time we say yes to one thing, we’re saying no to something else. Often times, taking on that additional commitment leads to sacrificing our sleep or quality time with loved ones. But why is it that setting boundaries can be so hard? Most of the time it’s because we don’t want to disappoint others, but over time taking on commitments in this way will lead to stress and burnout. So, before you say yes to a new opportunity, check in with yourself. What is my true reason for saying yes? What am I saying no to by potentially saying yes to this? Then, make a decision.</p>
<p><strong> 2. Rejuvenate for full engagement<br></strong>There’s no point in trying to trudge through a task when you don’t have the energy to do it effectively. When something could take one hour with laser focus, we instead drag on for fours hours with a scattered mind. So before starting the next thing check in. Am I fully present and energized? What do I need in order to rejuvenate my physical, mental, emotional, and spiritual energies?</p>
<p><strong> 3. Practice tapping into your being<br></strong>In a society that often seems like it prioritizes economic values more than human ones, we can easily get caught up in the hustle and bustle of to-do lists and notifications. So make it a practice to take a breath and enjoy the process. There’s no end goal. How can I slow down in my day to day? In what moments can I do nothing and just sit in full presence.</p>
<p><strong> 4. Don’t quit your daydream<br></strong>Delight in doing things for the sake of enjoyment. Dance because you love it. Write because it FEELS GOOD. Don’t limit yourself to activities that lead to achievement, success, or economic value. Make time for and practice joy and creativity. What pursuit brings me joy? What activity makes me FEEL GOOD? Then give yourself permission to do what makes your heart sing.</p>
<p> </p>
<p style="float: left;"><strong>﻿<img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0054/9489/8806/files/Ji-Youn_Kim_large.jpg?v=1546541451" style="float: left; margin-right: 20px;" width="213" height="213"> </strong></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<div>
<div><strong>Ji-Youn Kim</strong></div>
</div>
<div>
<div>Ji-Youn is a self-care &amp; performance coach and a wellness counsellor in-training. Through trauma-informed coaching, she helps ambitious individuals manage unpleasant emotions and optimize their energies through disciplined self-care. Find her online at<span> </span><a href="http://itsjiyounkim.com/" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://itsjiyounkim.com/&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1546623096300000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFtbTvm71uACm53PBaf3bo6MfKOxw" rel="noopener noreferrer">itsjiyounkim.com</a> or @itsjiyounkim on social media.</div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
